<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE Archive SYSTEM "http://greenstone.org/dtd/Archive/1.0/Archive.dtd">
<Archive>
<Section>
  <Description>
    <Metadata name="gsdldoctype">indexed_doc</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Language">en</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Encoding">utf8</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Author">davidm</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Title">pagea11.qxd</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="URL">http://C:/Users/SAKET/Greenstone/collect/audioboo/tmp/1544528996/beatles_georgeob.html</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="UTF8URL">http://C:/Users/SAKET/Greenstone/collect/audioboo/tmp/1544528996/beatles_georgeob.html</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="gsdlsourcefilename">import\wordpdf\beatles_georgeob.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="gsdlconvertedfilename">tmp\1544528996\beatles_georgeob.html</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="OrigSource">beatles_georgeob.html</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Source">beatles_georgeob.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="SourceFile">beatles_georgeob.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Plugin">PDFPlugin</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="FileSize">84054</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="FilenameRoot">beatles_georgeob</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="FileFormat">PDF</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="srcicon">_iconpdf_</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="srclink_file">doc.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="srclinkFile">doc.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="NumPages">1</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="dc.Format">Supplementary</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.ExifTool.ExifToolVersion">8.57</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.Directory">C:\Users\SAKET\Greenstone\collect\audioboo\import\wordpdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FileModifyDate">2018:12:10 07:46:28+03:00</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FileName">beatles_georgeob.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FilePermissions">666</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FileSize">84054</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FileType">PDF</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.MIMEType">application/pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.Author">davidm</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.CreateDate">1910:11:20 10:00:24</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.Creator">ADOBEPS4.DRV Version 4.10</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.Linearized">false</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.ModifyDate">2001:12:01 00:11:13</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.PDFVersion">1.2</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.PageCount">1</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.Producer">Acrobat Distiller 3.01 for Windows</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.Title">pagea11.qxd</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Identifier">HASH016a1c118d0ebce15ef6b87f</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="lastmodified">1544417188</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="lastmodifieddate">20181210</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="oailastmodified">1544528996</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="oailastmodifieddate">20181211</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="assocfilepath">HASH016a.dir</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="gsdlassocfile">doc.pdf:application/pdf:</Metadata>
  </Description>
  <Content>
&lt;A name=1&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Saturday, December 1, 2001&lt;br&gt;
Laredo Morning Times&lt;br&gt;
PAGE 11A&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;BEATLES&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Fans, musicians &lt;br&gt;mourn George &lt;br&gt;Harrison death&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;BY HILLEL ITALIE&lt;br&gt;Associated Press Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Paul McCartney called him ”my baby brother.” A fan&lt;br&gt;
thought him ”quiet and nice and powerful.” Musicians and&lt;br&gt;music lovers on Friday mourned the death of George&lt;br&gt;Harrison, the ”quiet Beatle” who fit in famously, if not always&lt;br&gt;happily, alongside his more colorful bandmates. &lt;br&gt;
”I am devastated and very, very sad,” McCartney told&lt;br&gt;
reporters outside his London home. ”He was a lovely guy&lt;br&gt;and a very brave man and had a wonderful sense of humor.&lt;br&gt;He is really just my baby brother.” &lt;br&gt;
Harrison, at 58 the youngest Beatle, died at 1:30 p.m.&lt;br&gt;
Thursday at a friend‘s Los Angeles home after a battle with&lt;br&gt;cancer, longtime friend Gavin De Becker told The&lt;br&gt;Associated Press late Thursday. Harrison‘s wife, Olivia, and&lt;br&gt;son Dhani, 24, were with him. &lt;br&gt;
”He left this world as he lived in it, conscious of God, fear-&lt;br&gt;
less of death, and at peace, surrounded by family and&lt;br&gt;friends,” the family said in a statement. &lt;br&gt;
With Harrison‘s death, two Beatles survive: McCartney&lt;br&gt;
and Ringo Starr. John Lennon was shot to death by a&lt;br&gt;deranged fan in 1980. &lt;br&gt;
The Beatles were four distinct personalities joined as a sin-&lt;br&gt;
gular force in the rebellious 1960s, influencing everything&lt;br&gt;from hair styles to music. Whether meditating, dropping acid&lt;br&gt;or sending up the squares in the film ”A Hard Day‘s Night,”&lt;br&gt;the band inspired millions. &lt;br&gt;
The story of the Beatles was as much a story of their fans:&lt;br&gt;
the rebels who identified with Lennon, the girls who fell for&lt;br&gt;Paul, the little kids who adored Ringo. &lt;br&gt;
Harrison‘s appeal was harder to define. He wasn‘t the&lt;br&gt;
cleverest Beatle, that was John. Paul was the cutest and&lt;br&gt;Ringo the most lovable. But something about Harrison —&lt;br&gt;the mysticism, the quiet competence, even the moodiness&lt;br&gt;— endeared him to fans and musicians alike. &lt;br&gt;
Edna McDonald, 49, from the Welsh mining town of Llanelli,&lt;br&gt;
recalled seeing the Beatles perform in Bristol, England, as a&lt;br&gt;teen-ager. While her friends chose Paul McCartney as their&lt;br&gt;favorite Beatle, she said she was drawn to Harrison. &lt;br&gt;
”He was quiet, different from the others,” McDonald, vaca-&lt;br&gt;
tioning in New York, said softly at Strawberry Fields, a Lennon&lt;br&gt;tribute site in Central Park. ”I respected him more for that. I&lt;br&gt;was always influenced by how he was a silent partner but had&lt;br&gt;a lot of influence on the group. It showed me that you could&lt;br&gt;be quiet and nice and powerful at the same time.” &lt;br&gt;
Ayessa Rourke, 43, a giraffe keeper at the Los Angeles&lt;br&gt;
Zoo, brought roses and wiped away tears at the Beatles star&lt;br&gt;on the Hollywood Walk of Fame. &lt;br&gt;
”He was just a lovely person and a great example of what a&lt;br&gt;
human can do, and the great things we are all capable of,” she said. &lt;br&gt;
As the news of his death spread, radio stations played&lt;br&gt;
music by the Beatles and by Harrison, and fans grieved.&lt;br&gt;They gathered at Strawberry Fields and left bouquets and&lt;br&gt;tributes at the gate of Harrison‘s 19th century Gothic man-&lt;br&gt;sion in Henley-on-Thames in England. &lt;br&gt;
But Harrison never cared for all the attention. He preferred&lt;br&gt;
being a musician to being a star, and soon soured on&lt;br&gt;Beatlemania — the screaming girls, the hair-tearing mobs,&lt;br&gt;the wild chases from limos to gigs and back to limos. Like&lt;br&gt;Lennon, his memories of the Beatles were tempered by&lt;br&gt;what he felt was lost in all the madness. &lt;br&gt;
”There was never anything, in any of the Beatle experiences&lt;br&gt;
really, that good: even the best thrill soon got tiring,” Harrison&lt;br&gt;wrote in his 1979 book, ”I, Me, Mine.” ”Your own space, man,&lt;br&gt;it‘s so important. That‘s why we were doomed, because we&lt;br&gt;didn‘t have any. We were like monkeys in a zoo.” &lt;br&gt;
Still, in a 1992 interview with The Daily Telegraph, Harrison&lt;br&gt;
confided: ”We had the time of our lives: We laughed for&lt;br&gt;years.” &lt;br&gt;
Peers enjoyed his company. He was close to Eric Clapton,&lt;br&gt;
Bob Dylan, Tom Petty and Jeff Lynne. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;


</Content>
</Section>
</Archive>
