<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE Archive SYSTEM "http://greenstone.org/dtd/Archive/1.0/Archive.dtd">
<Archive>
<Section>
  <Description>
    <Metadata name="gsdldoctype">indexed_doc</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Language">en</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Encoding">utf8</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Title">Microsoft Word - User_en.doc</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="URL">http://C:/Program Files/Greenstone/tmp/F728.html</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="UTF8URL">http://C:/Program Files/Greenstone/tmp/F728.html</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="gsdlsourcefilename">import\greenstone.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="gsdlconvertedfilename">C:\Program Files\Greenstone\tmp\F728.html</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="OrigSource">F728.html</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Source">greenstone.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="SourceFile">greenstone.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Plugin">PDFPlugin</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="FileSize">1195102</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="FilenameRoot">greenstone</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="FileFormat">PDF</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="srcicon">_iconpdf_</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="srclink_file">doc.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="srclinkFile">doc.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="NumPages">88</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.ExifTool.ExifToolVersion">8.57</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.Directory">C:\Program Files\Greenstone\collect\ebook\import</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FileModifyDate">2018:12:17 09:16:22-08:00</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FileName">greenstone.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FilePermissions">666</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FileSize">1195102</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FileType">PDF</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.MIMEType">application/pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.Author">kjdon</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.CreateDate">2005:04:13 08:52:24+12:00</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.Creator">kjdon</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.Linearized">true</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.ModifyDate">2005:04:13 08:52:24+12:00</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.PDFVersion">1.3</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.PageCount">88</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.Producer">Acrobat Distiller 5.0.5 &amp;#40;Windows&amp;#41;</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.Title">Microsoft Word - User_en.doc</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.Author">kjdon</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.CreateDate">2005:04:13 08:52:24+12:00</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.CreationDate">2005:04:12 20:52:24Z</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.Creator">kjdon</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.MetadataDate">2005:04:12 20:52:24Z</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.ModDate">2005:04:12 20:52:24Z</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.ModifyDate">2005:04:13 08:52:24+12:00</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.Producer">Acrobat Distiller 5.0.5 &amp;#40;Windows&amp;#41;</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.Title">Microsoft Word - User_en.doc</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Identifier">HASH014971a9a365c84627ba6729</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="lastmodified">1545066982</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="lastmodifieddate">20181217</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="oailastmodified">1545141406</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="oailastmodifieddate">20181218</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="assocfilepath">HASH0149.dir</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="gsdlassocfile">doc.pdf:application/pdf:</Metadata>
  </Description>
  <Content>
&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greenstone gsdl-2.60  March 2005 &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;GREENSTONE DIGITAL LIBRARY &lt;br /&gt;USER’S GUIDE &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ian H. Witten, Stefan Boddie and John Thompson &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Department of Computer Science &lt;br /&gt;University of Waikato, New Zealand &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greenstone is a suite of software for building and distributing digital &lt;br /&gt;library collections. It provides a new way of organizing information &lt;br /&gt;and publishing it on the Internet or on CD-ROM. Greenstone is &lt;br /&gt;produced by the New Zealand Digital Library Project at the University &lt;br /&gt;of Waikato, and developed and distributed in cooperation with &lt;br /&gt;UNESCO and the Human Info NGO. It is open-source software, &lt;br /&gt;available from http://greenstone.org under the terms of the GNU &lt;br /&gt;General Public License. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;We want to ensure that this software works well for you. Please &lt;br /&gt;report any problems to greenstone@cs.waikato.ac.nz &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;ii &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;About this manual &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This manual provides a comprehensive description of how to use the &lt;br /&gt;Greenstone software for accessing and building digital library collections. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Section 1 gives an overview of the capabilities of the software. Section 2 &lt;br /&gt;explains how to use Greenstone collections. The interface is self-&lt;br /&gt;explanatory—the best way to learn is by doing—and this section &lt;br /&gt;comprises the on-line help information for a typical collection. Section 3 &lt;br /&gt;explains how to build your own library collections using the Greenstone &lt;br /&gt;Librarian Interface. Section 4 introduces the administration facility that &lt;br /&gt;allows the system administrator to monitor what is going on and control &lt;br /&gt;who can build collections. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Appendices list the features of the Greenstone software, and give a &lt;br /&gt;glossary of terms used throughout the Greenstone documentation. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Companion documents &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The complete set of Greenstone documents includes four volumes:  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Greenstone Digital Library Installer’s Guide &lt;br /&gt;• Greenstone Digital Library User’s Guide (this document) &lt;br /&gt;• Greenstone Digital Library Developer’s Guide &lt;br /&gt;• Greenstone Digital Library: From Paper to Collection &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;iii &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Acknowledgements &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Greenstone software is a collaborative effort between many people. &lt;br /&gt;Rodger McNab and Stefan Boddie are the principal architects and &lt;br /&gt;implementors.  Contributions have been made by David Bainbridge, &lt;br /&gt;George Buchanan, Hong Chen, Michael Dewsnip, Katherine Don, Elke &lt;br /&gt;Duncker, Carl Gutwin, Geoff Holmes, Dana McKay, John McPherson, &lt;br /&gt;Craig Nevill-Manning, Dynal Patel, Gordon Paynter, Bernhard &lt;br /&gt;Pfahringer, Todd Reed, Bill Rogers, John Thompson, and Stuart Yeates. &lt;br /&gt;Other members of the New Zealand Digital Library project provided &lt;br /&gt;advice and inspiration in the design of the system: Mark Apperley, Sally &lt;br /&gt;Jo Cunningham, Matt Jones, Steve Jones, Te Taka Keegan, Michel Loots, &lt;br /&gt;Malika Mahoui, Gary Marsden, Dave Nichols and Lloyd Smith. We &lt;br /&gt;would also like to acknowledge all those who have contributed to the &lt;br /&gt;GNU-licensed packages included in this distribution: MG, GDBM, &lt;br /&gt;PDFTOHTML, PERL, WGET, WVWARE and XLHTML. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;greenstone.org  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contents &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;About this manual ii &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 OVERVIEW OF GREENSTONE 1 &lt;br /&gt;1.1 Collections 1 &lt;br /&gt;1.2 Finding information 2 &lt;br /&gt;1.3 Document formats 2 &lt;br /&gt;1.4 Multimedia and multilingual documents 3 &lt;br /&gt;1.5 Distributing Greenstone 3 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;2 USING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 5 &lt;br /&gt;2.1 Using a Greenstone CD-ROM 5 &lt;br /&gt;2.2 Finding information 6 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;How to find information 7 &lt;br /&gt;How to read the documents 8 &lt;br /&gt;What the icons mean 9 &lt;br /&gt;How to search for particular words 9 &lt;br /&gt;Scope of queries 11 &lt;br /&gt;Advanced search features 11 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;2.3 Changing the preferences 13 &lt;br /&gt;Collection preferences 13 &lt;br /&gt;Language preferences 13 &lt;br /&gt;Presentation preferences 14 &lt;br /&gt;Search preferences 15 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;3 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 17 &lt;br /&gt;3.1 The librarian’s interface 18 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Getting started 18 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;v &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assembling the source material 20 &lt;br /&gt;Enriching the documents 22 &lt;br /&gt;Designing the collection 28 &lt;br /&gt;Building the collection 30 &lt;br /&gt;Previewing 30 &lt;br /&gt;Help 31 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;3.2 Librarian Interface user guide 31 &lt;br /&gt;Starting Off 31 &lt;br /&gt;Downloading Files From the Internet 32 &lt;br /&gt;Collecting Files for Your Collection 33 &lt;br /&gt;Enriching the Collection with Metadata 36 &lt;br /&gt;Designing Your Collection's Appearance 41 &lt;br /&gt;Producing Your Collection 49 &lt;br /&gt;Miscellaneous 50 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;3.3 Tagging document files 52 &lt;br /&gt;3.4 The Collector 55 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Logging in 56 &lt;br /&gt;Dialog structure 57 &lt;br /&gt;Collection information 58 &lt;br /&gt;Source data 59 &lt;br /&gt;Configuring the collection 63 &lt;br /&gt;Building the collection 64 &lt;br /&gt;Viewing the collection 65 &lt;br /&gt;Working with existing collections 65 &lt;br /&gt;Document formats 67 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;4 ADMINISTRATION 69 &lt;br /&gt;4.1 Configuration files 72 &lt;br /&gt;4.2 Logs 72 &lt;br /&gt;4.3 User management 73 &lt;br /&gt;4.4 Technical information 74 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;APPENDIX A SOFTWARE FEATURES 75 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;APPENDIX B  GLOSSARY OF TERMS 79 &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;greenstone.org  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 &lt;br /&gt;Overview of Greenstone &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greenstone is a comprehensive system for constructing and presenting &lt;br /&gt;collections of thousands or millions of documents, including text, images, &lt;br /&gt;audio and video.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1.1 Collections  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A typical digital library built with Greenstone will contain many &lt;br /&gt;collections, individually organized—though they bear a strong family &lt;br /&gt;resemblance. Easily maintained, collections can be augmented and rebuilt &lt;br /&gt;automatically.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are several ways to find information in most Greenstone &lt;br /&gt;collections. For example, you can search for particular words that appear &lt;br /&gt;in the text, or within a section of a document. You can browse documents &lt;br /&gt;by title: just click on a book to read it. You can browse documents by &lt;br /&gt;subject. Subjects are represented by bookshelves: just click on a &lt;br /&gt;bookshelf to look at the books. Where appropriate, documents come &lt;br /&gt;complete with a table of contents: you can click on a chapter or &lt;br /&gt;subsection to open it, expand the full table of contents, or expand the full &lt;br /&gt;document into your browser window (useful for printing). The New &lt;br /&gt;Zealand Digital Library website (nzdl.org) provides numerous example &lt;br /&gt;collections. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the front page of each collection is a statement of its purpose and &lt;br /&gt;coverage, and an explanation of how the collection is organized. Most &lt;br /&gt;collections can be accessed by both searching and browsing. When &lt;br /&gt;searching, the Greenstone software looks through the entire text of all &lt;br /&gt;documents in the collection (this is called “full-text search”). In most &lt;br /&gt;collections the user can choose between indexes built from different parts &lt;br /&gt;of the documents. Some collections have an index of full documents, an &lt;br /&gt;index of paragraphs, and an index of titles, each of which can be searched &lt;br /&gt;for particular words or phrases. Using these you can find all documents &lt;br /&gt;that contain a particular set of words (the words may be scattered far and &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;2 OVERVIEW OF GREENSTONE &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;wide throughout the document), or all paragraphs that contain the set of &lt;br /&gt;words (which must all appear in the same paragraph), or all documents &lt;br /&gt;whose titles contain the words (the words must all appear in the &lt;br /&gt;document’s title). There might be other indexes, perhaps an index of &lt;br /&gt;sections, and an index of section headings. Browsing involves lists that &lt;br /&gt;the user can examine: lists of authors, lists of titles, lists of dates, &lt;br /&gt;hierarchical classification structures, and so on. Different collections offer &lt;br /&gt;different browsing facilities.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1.2 Finding information  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greenstone constructs full-text indexes from the document text—that is, &lt;br /&gt;indexes that enable searching on any words in the full text of the &lt;br /&gt;document. Indexes can be searched for particular words, combinations of &lt;br /&gt;words, or phrases, and results are ordered according to how relevant they &lt;br /&gt;are to the query.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In most collections, descriptive data such as author, title, date, keywords, &lt;br /&gt;and so on, is associated with each document. This information is called &lt;br /&gt;metadata. Many document collections also contain full-text indexes of &lt;br /&gt;certain kinds of metadata. For example, many collections have a &lt;br /&gt;searchable index of document titles. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Users can browse interactively around lists, and hierarchical structures, &lt;br /&gt;that are generated from the metadata that is associated with each &lt;br /&gt;document in the collection. Metadata forms the raw material for &lt;br /&gt;browsing. It must be provided explicitly or be derivable automatically &lt;br /&gt;from the documents themselves. Different collections offer different &lt;br /&gt;searching and browsing facilities. Indexes for both searching and &lt;br /&gt;browsing are constructed during a “building” process, according to &lt;br /&gt;information in a collection configuration file. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greenstone creates all index structures automatically from the documents &lt;br /&gt;and suppporting files: nothing is done manually. If new documents in the &lt;br /&gt;same format become available, they can be merged into the collection &lt;br /&gt;automatically. Indeed, for many collections this is done by processes that &lt;br /&gt;awake regularly, scout for new material, and rebuild the indexes—all &lt;br /&gt;without manual intervention.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1.3 Document formats  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Source documents come in a variety of formats, and are converted into a &lt;br /&gt;standard XML form for indexing by “plugins.” Plugins distributed with &lt;br /&gt;Greenstone process plain text, HTML, WORD and PDF documents, and &lt;br /&gt;Usenet and E-mail messages. New ones can be written for different &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;OVERVIEW OF GREENSTONE 3 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;document types (to do this you need to study the Greenstone Digital &lt;br /&gt;Library Developer’s Guide). To build browsing structures from metadata, &lt;br /&gt;an analogous scheme of “classifiers” is used. These create browsing &lt;br /&gt;indexes of various kinds: scrollable lists, alphabetic selectors, dates, and &lt;br /&gt;arbitrary hierarchies. Again, Greenstone programmers can create new &lt;br /&gt;browsing structures. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1.4 Multimedia and multilingual documents  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collections can contain text, pictures, audio and video. Non-textual &lt;br /&gt;material is either linked into the textual documents or accompanied by &lt;br /&gt;textual descriptions (such as figure captions) to allow full-text searching &lt;br /&gt;and browsing. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unicode, which is a standard scheme for representing the character sets &lt;br /&gt;used in the world’s languages, is used throughout Greenstone. This allows &lt;br /&gt;any language to be processed and displayed in a consistent manner. &lt;br /&gt;Collections have been built containing Arabic, Chinese, English, French, &lt;br /&gt;Mäori and Spanish. Multilingual collections embody automatic language &lt;br /&gt;recognition, and the interface is available in all the above languages (and &lt;br /&gt;more). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1.5 Distributing Greenstone &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collections are accessed over the Internet or published, in precisely the &lt;br /&gt;same form, on a self-installing Windows CD-ROM. Compression is used &lt;br /&gt;to compact the text and indexes. A Corba protocol supports distributed &lt;br /&gt;collections and graphical query interfaces. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The New Zealand Digital Library (nzdl.org) provides many example &lt;br /&gt;collections, including historical documents, humanitarian and &lt;br /&gt;development information, technical reports and bibliographies, literary &lt;br /&gt;works, and magazines. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being open source, Greenstone is readily extensible, and benefits from &lt;br /&gt;the inclusion of GNU-licensed modules for full-text retrieval, database &lt;br /&gt;management, and text extraction from proprietary document formats. &lt;br /&gt;Only through international cooperative efforts will digital library software &lt;br /&gt;become sufficiently comprehensive to meet the world’s needs with the &lt;br /&gt;richness and flexibility that users deserve. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;4 OVERVIEW OF GREENSTONE &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;greenstone.org  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;2 &lt;br /&gt;Using Greenstone Collections &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Greenstone software is designed to be easy to use. Web-based and &lt;br /&gt;CD-ROM collections have interfaces that are identical. Installing the &lt;br /&gt;Greenstone software from CD-ROM on any Windows or Linux computer &lt;br /&gt;is very easy indeed; a standard installation setup program is used in &lt;br /&gt;conjunction with pre-compiled binaries. A collection can be used locally &lt;br /&gt;on the computer where it is installed; also, if this computer is connected &lt;br /&gt;to a network, the software automatically and transparently allows all other &lt;br /&gt;computers on the network to access the same collection. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next section describes how to install a Greenstone CD-ROM. Then &lt;br /&gt;we look at the searching and browsing facilities offered by a typical &lt;br /&gt;Greenstone collection, the “Demo” collection that is supplied with the &lt;br /&gt;Greenstone software. Other collections offer similar facilities; if you can &lt;br /&gt;use one, you can use them all. The following section explains how to &lt;br /&gt;customize the interface for your own requirements using the Preferences &lt;br /&gt;page. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;2.1 Using a Greenstone CD-ROM &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Greenstone digital library software itself comes on a CD-ROM, and &lt;br /&gt;you or your system manager have probably installed it on your system, &lt;br /&gt;following the instructions in the Greenstone Digital Library Installer’s &lt;br /&gt;Guide. If so, Greenstone is already installed on your computer and you &lt;br /&gt;should skip the rest of this section. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some Greenstone collections come on a self-contained Greenstone CD-&lt;br /&gt;ROM that includes enough of the software to run just that collection. To &lt;br /&gt;use it, simply put it into the CD-ROM drive on any Windows PC. Most &lt;br /&gt;likely (if “autorun” is enabled on your PC), a window will appear inviting &lt;br /&gt;you to install the Greenstone software. If not, find the CD-ROM disk &lt;br /&gt;drive (on current Windows systems you can get this by clicking on the My &lt;br /&gt;Computer icon on the desktop) and double-click it, then the Setup.exe file &lt;br /&gt;inside it. The Greenstone Setup program will be entered, which guides &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;6 USING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;you through the setup procedure. Most people respond yes to all the &lt;br /&gt;questions.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When the installation procedure has finished, you’ll find the library in the &lt;br /&gt;Programs submenu of the Windows Start menu, under the name of the &lt;br /&gt;collection (for example, “Development Library” or “United Nations &lt;br /&gt;University”). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once the software has been installed, the library will be entered &lt;br /&gt;automatically every time you re-insert the CD-ROM if autorun is enabled. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;2.2 Finding information  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to learn how to use a Greenstone collection is to try it &lt;br /&gt;out. Don’t worry—you can’t break anything. Click liberally: most images &lt;br /&gt;that appear on the screen are clickable. If you hold the mouse stationary &lt;br /&gt;over an image, most browsers will soon pop up a message that tells you &lt;br /&gt;what will happen if you click.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experiment! Choose common words like “the” and “and” to search for—&lt;br /&gt;that should evoke some responses, and nothing will break.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greenstone digital library systems usually comprise several separate &lt;br /&gt;collections—for example, computer science technical reports, literary &lt;br /&gt;works, internet FAQs, magazines. There will be a home page for the &lt;br /&gt;digital library system which allows you to access any publicly-accessible &lt;br /&gt;collection; in addition, each collection has its own “about” page that gives &lt;br /&gt;you information about how the collection is organized and the principles &lt;br /&gt;governing what is included in it. To get back to the “about” page at any &lt;br /&gt;time, just click on the “collection” icon that appears at the top left side of &lt;br /&gt;all searching and browsing pages. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 1 shows a screenshot of the “Demo” collection supplied with the &lt;br /&gt;Greenstone software, which is a very small subset of the Development &lt;br /&gt;Library collection; we will use it as an example to describe the different &lt;br /&gt;ways of finding information. (If you can’t find the Demo collection, use &lt;br /&gt;the Development Library instead; it looks just the same.) First, almost all &lt;br /&gt;icons are clickable. Several icons appear at the top of almost every page; &lt;br /&gt;Table 1 shows you what they mean. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;USING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 7 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The “search … subjects … titles a-z … organization … how to” bar &lt;br /&gt;underneath gives access to the searching and browsing facilities. The &lt;br /&gt;leftmost button is for searching, and the ones to the right of it—four, in &lt;br /&gt;this collection—evoke different browsing facilities. These last four may &lt;br /&gt;differ from one collection to another.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;How to find information &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Table 2 shows the five ways to find information in the Demo collection. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can search for particular words that appear in the text from the &lt;br /&gt;“search” page. (This is just like the “about” page shown in Figure 1, &lt;br /&gt;except that it doesn’t contain the about this collection text.) The search &lt;br /&gt;page can be reached from other pages by pressing the search button. You &lt;br /&gt;can access publications by subject by pressing the subjects button. This &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Table 1 What the icons at the top of each page mean &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This takes you to the “about” page &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This takes you to the Digital Library’s home page, from which you can&lt;br /&gt;select another collection &lt;br /&gt;This provides help text similar to what you are reading now &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This allows you to set some user interface and searching options that&lt;br /&gt;will then be used henceforth &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 1 &lt;br /&gt;Using the Demo &lt;br /&gt;collection &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;8 USING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;brings up a list of subjects, represented by bookshelves that can be further &lt;br /&gt;expanded by clicking on them. You can access publications by title by &lt;br /&gt;pressing the titles a-z button. This brings up a list of books in alphabetic &lt;br /&gt;order. You can access publications by organization by pressing the &lt;br /&gt;organization button. This brings up a list of organizations. You can &lt;br /&gt;access publications by how to listing by pressing the how to button. This &lt;br /&gt;brings up a list of “how to” hints. All these buttons are visible in Figure 1. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;How to read the documents &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the Demo collection, you can tell when you have arrived at an &lt;br /&gt;individual book because there is a photograph of its front cover (Figure &lt;br /&gt;2). Beside the photograph is a table of contents: the entry in bold face &lt;br /&gt;marks where you are, in this case Introduction and Summary—Section 1 &lt;br /&gt;of the chosen book. This table is expandable: click on the folders to open &lt;br /&gt;them or close them. Click on the open book at the top to close it.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Underneath is the text of the current section (“The international demand &lt;br /&gt;for tropical butterflies …” in the example, beginning at the very bottom of &lt;br /&gt;the illustration). When you have read through it, there are arrows at the &lt;br /&gt;end to take you on to the next section or back to the previous one.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Below the photograph are four buttons. Click on detach to make a new &lt;br /&gt;browser window for this book. (This is useful if you want to compare &lt;br /&gt;books, or read two at once.) If you have reached this book through a &lt;br /&gt;search, the search terms will be highlighted: the no highlighting button &lt;br /&gt;turns this off. Click on expand text to expand out the whole text of the &lt;br /&gt;current section, or book. Click on expand contents to expand out the &lt;br /&gt;whole table of contents so that you can see the titles of all chapters and &lt;br /&gt;subsections.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In some collections, the documents do not have this kind of hierarchical &lt;br /&gt;structure. In this case, no table of contents is displayed when you get to an &lt;br /&gt;individual document—just the document text. In some cases, the &lt;br /&gt;document is split into pages, and you can read sequentially or jump about &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Table 2 What the icons on the search/browse bar mean  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Search for particular words &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Access publications by subject &lt;br /&gt;Access publications by title &lt;br /&gt;Access publications by organization &lt;br /&gt;Access publications by “how to” listing &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;USING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 9 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;from one page to another. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;What the icons mean &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you are browsing around the collection, you will encounter the &lt;br /&gt;items shown in Table 3.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;How to search for particular words &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the search page, follow these simple steps to make a query: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Specify what units you want to search: in the Demo collection you &lt;br /&gt;can search section titles or the full text of the books.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 2 &lt;br /&gt;A book in the Demo &lt;br /&gt;collection &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;10 USING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Say whether you want to search for all or just some of the words  &lt;br /&gt;• Type in the words you want to search for into the query box &lt;br /&gt;• Click the Begin Search button  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you make a query, the titles of up to twenty matching documents &lt;br /&gt;will be shown. There is a button at the end to take you on to the next &lt;br /&gt;twenty. From there you will find buttons to take you on to the third &lt;br /&gt;twenty or back to the first twenty, and so on. However, for efficiency &lt;br /&gt;reasons a maximum of 100 is imposed on the number of documents &lt;br /&gt;returned. You can change these numbers by clicking the preferences &lt;br /&gt;button at the top of the page. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click the title of any document, or the little icon beside it, to open it. The &lt;br /&gt;icon may show a book, or a folder, or a page: it will be a book icon if you &lt;br /&gt;are searching books; otherwise if you are searching sections it will be a &lt;br /&gt;folder or page icon depending on whether or not the section found has &lt;br /&gt;subsections. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Search terms  Whatever you type into the query box is interpreted as a list of words &lt;br /&gt;called “search terms.” Each search term contains nothing but alphabetic &lt;br /&gt;characters and digits. Terms are separated by white space. If any other &lt;br /&gt;characters such as punctuation appear, they serve to separate terms just as &lt;br /&gt;though they were spaces. And then they are ignored. You can’t search for &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Table 3 Icons that you will encounter when browsing &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click on a book icon to read the corresponding book &lt;br /&gt;Click on a bookshelf icon to look at books on that subject &lt;br /&gt;View this document &lt;br /&gt;Open this folder and view contents &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click on this icon to close the book &lt;br /&gt;Click on this icon to close the folder &lt;br /&gt;Click on the arrow to go on to the next section ... &lt;br /&gt;... or back to the previous section &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open this page in a new window &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Expand table of contents &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Display all text &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Highlight search terms &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;USING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 11 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;words that include punctuation.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, the query &lt;br /&gt;Agro-forestry in the Pacific Islands: Systems for &lt;br /&gt;Sustainability (1993) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;will be treated the same as &lt;br /&gt;Agro forestry in the Pacific Islands Systems for &lt;br /&gt;Sustainability 1993  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Query type  There are two different kinds of query. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Queries for all the words. These look for documents (or chapters, or &lt;br /&gt;titles) that contain all the words you have specified. Documents that &lt;br /&gt;satisfy the query are displayed. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Queries for some of the words. Just list some terms that are likely to &lt;br /&gt;appear in the documents you are looking for. Documents are &lt;br /&gt;displayed in order of how closely they match the query. When &lt;br /&gt;determining the degree of match,  &lt;br /&gt;• the more search terms a document contains, the closer it &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;matches;  &lt;br /&gt;• rare terms are more important than common ones;  &lt;br /&gt;• short documents match better than long ones.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use as many search terms as you like—a whole sentence, or even a whole &lt;br /&gt;paragraph. If you specify only one term, it doesn’t much matter whether &lt;br /&gt;you use an all or a some query, except that in the second case the results &lt;br /&gt;will be sorted by the search term’s frequency of occurrence. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scope of queries &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In most collections you can choose different indexes to search. For &lt;br /&gt;example, there might be author or title indexes. Or there might be chapter &lt;br /&gt;or paragraph indexes. Generally, the full matching document is returned &lt;br /&gt;regardless of which index you search.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If documents are books, they will be opened at the appropriate place. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advanced search features &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the above is enough to meet most searching needs, some more &lt;br /&gt;advanced search features are provided. These are activated from the &lt;br /&gt;Preferences page, which is reached by clicking the preferences button at &lt;br /&gt;the top of the page—see Section 2.3 below. After changing your &lt;br /&gt;preferences, do not click your browser’s Back button—that would undo &lt;br /&gt;the changes. Instead, click any of the buttons on the search/browse bar.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;12 USING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Case sensitivity and stemming &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you specify search terms, you can choose whether upper and lower &lt;br /&gt;case must match between the query and the document: this is called “case &lt;br /&gt;sensitivity.” You can also choose whether to ignore word endings or not: &lt;br /&gt;this is called “stemming.” &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under Search options on the Preferences page you will see a pair of &lt;br /&gt;buttons labeled ignore case differences and upper/lower case must match; &lt;br /&gt;these control the case sensitivity of your queries. Below is a pair of &lt;br /&gt;buttons labeled ignore word endings and whole word must match: these &lt;br /&gt;control stemming. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, if the buttons ignore case differences and ignore word &lt;br /&gt;endings are selected, the query &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;African building &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;will be treated the same as &lt;br /&gt;africa builds &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;because the uppercase letter in “African” will be transformed to &lt;br /&gt;lowercase, and the suffixes “n” and “ing” will be removed from “African” &lt;br /&gt;and “building” respectively (also, “s” would be removed from “builds”).  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Generally case differences and word endings should be ignored unless &lt;br /&gt;you are querying for particular names or acronyms.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Phrase searching  If your query includes a phrase in quotation marks, only documents &lt;br /&gt;containing that phrase, exactly as typed, will be returned.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to use phrase searching, you need to learn a little about how it &lt;br /&gt;works. Phrases are processed by a post-retrieval scan. First the query is &lt;br /&gt;issued in the normal way—all the words in the phrase are included as &lt;br /&gt;search terms—and then the documents returned are scanned to eliminate &lt;br /&gt;those in which that phrase does not appear.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the post-retrieval scan, phrases are checked just as they are, &lt;br /&gt;including any punctuation. For example, the query &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;what’s a “post-retrieval scan?” &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;will first retrieve all documents that match all of the words &lt;br /&gt;what s a post retrieval scan &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;and then the documents returned will be checked for the phrase &lt;br /&gt;post-retrieval scan? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Phrase matches are case-insensitive if ignore case differences is set on the &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;USING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 13 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Preferences page. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advanced query mode  In advanced query mode, which can be selected on the Preferences page, &lt;br /&gt;the queries for all of the words, described above, are actually Boolean &lt;br /&gt;queries. They consist of a list of terms joined by logical operators &amp;amp; &lt;br /&gt;(and), | (or), and ! (not). Absent operators between search terms are &lt;br /&gt;interpreted as &amp;amp; (and): thus a query without any operators returns &lt;br /&gt;documents that match all the terms. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the words AND, OR, and NOT appear in your query they are treated as &lt;br /&gt;ordinary search terms, not operators. For operators you must use &amp;amp;, |, and &lt;br /&gt;!. In addition, parentheses can be used for grouping.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using search history  When you switch on the “search history” feature on the Preferences page &lt;br /&gt;you will be shown your last few searches, along with a summary of how &lt;br /&gt;many results they generated. Click the button beside one of the previous &lt;br /&gt;searches to copy the text into the search box. This makes it easy to repeat &lt;br /&gt;slightly modified versions of previous queries.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;2.3 Changing the preferences &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you click the preferences button at the top of the page you will be &lt;br /&gt;able to change some features of the interface to suit your own &lt;br /&gt;requirements. The preferences depend on the collection; an example is &lt;br /&gt;shown in Figure 3. When you adjust your search preferences, you should &lt;br /&gt;press the set preferences button shown in Figure 3. After setting &lt;br /&gt;preferences, do not use your browser’s “back” button—that would unset &lt;br /&gt;them! Instead, click one of the buttons on the access bar near the top of &lt;br /&gt;the page. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collection preferences &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some collections comprise several subcollections, which can be searched &lt;br /&gt;independently or together, as one unit. If so, you can select which &lt;br /&gt;subcollections to include in your searches on the Preferences page.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Language preferences &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each collection has a default presentation language, but you can switch to &lt;br /&gt;a different language if you like. You can also alter the encoding scheme &lt;br /&gt;used by Greenstone for output to the browser—the software chooses &lt;br /&gt;sensible defaults, but with some browsers better visual results can be used  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;by switching to a different encoding scheme. All collections allow you to &lt;br /&gt;switch from the standard graphical interface format to a textual one. This &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;14 USING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;is particularly useful for visually impaired users who use large screen &lt;br /&gt;fonts or speech synthesizers for output.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Presentation preferences &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Depending on the collection, there may be other options you can set that &lt;br /&gt;control the presentation. Collections of web pages allow you to suppress &lt;br /&gt;the Greenstone navigation bar at the top of each document page, so that &lt;br /&gt;once you have done a search you land at the exact web page that matches &lt;br /&gt;without any Greenstone header. To do another search you will have to use &lt;br /&gt;your browser’s “back” button. These collections also allow you to &lt;br /&gt;suppress Greenstone’s warning message when you click a link that takes &lt;br /&gt;you out of the digital library collection and on to the web itself. And in &lt;br /&gt;some web collections you can control whether the links on the “Search &lt;br /&gt;Results” page take you straight to the actual URL in question, rather than &lt;br /&gt;to the digital library’s copy of the page.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 3 &lt;br /&gt;The Preferences page &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;USING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 15 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Search preferences &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under Search preferences in Figure 3, the first pair of buttons allows you &lt;br /&gt;to get a large query box, so that you can easily do paragraph-sized &lt;br /&gt;searching. In Greenstone, it is surprisingly quick to search for large &lt;br /&gt;amounts of text. The next two pairs of buttons control the kind of text &lt;br /&gt;matching in the searches that you make. The first set (labeled “case &lt;br /&gt;differences”) controls whether upper and lower case must match. The &lt;br /&gt;second (“word endings”) controls whether to ignore word endings or not. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using the next button pair you can switch to the “advanced” query mode &lt;br /&gt;described above, which allows you to specify more precise queries by &lt;br /&gt;combining terms using AND (&amp;amp;), OR (|), and NOT (!). You can turn the &lt;br /&gt;search history feature, described above, on and off. Finally, you can &lt;br /&gt;control the number of hits returned, and the number presented on each &lt;br /&gt;screenful, through the last entry in Figure 3. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;16 USING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;greenstone.org  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;3 &lt;br /&gt;Making Greenstone &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collections &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The simplest way to build new collections is to use Greenstone’s &lt;br /&gt;“librarian” interface (GLI). This allows you to collect sets of documents, &lt;br /&gt;import or assign metadata, and build them into a Greenstone collection. It &lt;br /&gt;supports five basic activities, which can be interleaved but are nominally &lt;br /&gt;undertaken in this order: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. Copy documents from the computer’s file space, including existing &lt;br /&gt;collections, into the new collection. Any existing metadata remains &lt;br /&gt;“attached” to these documents. Documents may also be gathered &lt;br /&gt;from the web through a built-in mirroring facility. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. Enrich the documents by adding further metadata to individual &lt;br /&gt;documents or groups of documents. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;3. Design the collection by determining its appearance and the access &lt;br /&gt;facilities that it will support. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;4. Build the collection using Greenstone. &lt;br /&gt;5. Preview the newly created collection, which will have been installed &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;on your Greenstone home page as one of the regular collections. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The librarian interface allows you to add what people call “external” &lt;br /&gt;metadata to documents, metadata that pertains to the document as a &lt;br /&gt;whole. But documents often need to be structured into sections and &lt;br /&gt;subsections, and “internal” metadata might be associated with each part. &lt;br /&gt;In Greenstone, source documents can be tagged with this information, and &lt;br /&gt;we explain this in Section 3.3. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, an alternative way of building collections is provided by the &lt;br /&gt;Collector, which helps you create new collections, modify or add to &lt;br /&gt;existing ones, or delete collections. It predates the librarian interface, and &lt;br /&gt;for most practical purposes the librarian interface should be used instead &lt;br /&gt;of the Collector. It is described in Section 3.4. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;18 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To harness the full power of Greenstone to build advanced collections, &lt;br /&gt;you will also need to read Chapter 2 of the Developer’s Guide. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;3.1 The librarian’s interface &lt;br /&gt;To convey the operation of Greenstone’s librarian interface, we work &lt;br /&gt;through a simple example. Figures 4 to 15 are screen snapshots at various &lt;br /&gt;points during the interaction. This example uses documents in the &lt;br /&gt;Development Library Subset (DLS) collection, which is distributed with &lt;br /&gt;Greenstone. For expository purposes, the walkthrough takes the form of a &lt;br /&gt;single pass through the steps listed above. A more realistic pattern of use, &lt;br /&gt;however, is for users to switch back and forth through the various stages &lt;br /&gt;as the task proceeds. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The librarian interface can be run in one of four modes: Librarian &lt;br /&gt;Assistant, Librarian, Library Systems Specialist, and Expert. Modes &lt;br /&gt;control the level of detail within the interface, and can be changed &lt;br /&gt;through ‘Preferences’ in the ‘File’ menu. The walkthrough in this section &lt;br /&gt;assumes that the librarian interface is operating in the default mode, &lt;br /&gt;Librarian. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Getting started &lt;br /&gt;Launch the librarian interface under Windows by selecting Greenstone &lt;br /&gt;Digital Library from the Programs section of the Start menu and &lt;br /&gt;choosing Librarian Interface. If you are using Unix, instead type  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;cd ~/gsdl &lt;br /&gt;cd gli &lt;br /&gt;./gli.sh &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;where ~/gsdl is the directory containing your Greenstone system. To &lt;br /&gt;begin, you must either open an existing collection or start a new one. &lt;br /&gt;Figure 4 shows the user in the process of starting a new collection. She &lt;br /&gt;has selected New from the file menu and begun to fill out general &lt;br /&gt;information about the collection—its title, the E-mail address of the &lt;br /&gt;person responsible for it, and a brief description of the content—in the &lt;br /&gt;popup window. The collection title is a short phrase used throughout the &lt;br /&gt;digital library to identify the collection’s content: existing collections &lt;br /&gt;have names like Food and Nutrition Library, World Environmental &lt;br /&gt;Library, and so on. When you type the title, the system assigns a unique &lt;br /&gt;mnemonic identifier, the collection “name”, for internal use (you can &lt;br /&gt;change it if you like). The E-mail address specifies the first point of &lt;br /&gt;contact for any problems encountered with the collection. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The brief description is a statement describing the principles that govern &lt;br /&gt;what is included in the collection. It appears under the heading About this &lt;br /&gt;collection on the collection’s initial page.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 19 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 4. Starting a &lt;br /&gt;new collection &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 5. Exploring &lt;br /&gt;the local file space &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;20 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;At this point, the user decides whether to base the new collection on the &lt;br /&gt;same structure as an existing collection, or to build an entirely new kind &lt;br /&gt;of collection. In Figure 4 she has chosen to base it on the Development &lt;br /&gt;Library Subset collection. This implies that the “DLS” metadata set which &lt;br /&gt;is used in this collection will be used for the new collection. (In fact, this &lt;br /&gt;metadata set has been used to build several Greenstone collections that &lt;br /&gt;share a common structure and organization but with different content, &lt;br /&gt;including the Development Library Subset and Demo collections &lt;br /&gt;delivered as samples with Greenstone.) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The DLS metadata set contains these items: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Title &lt;br /&gt;• Subject &lt;br /&gt;• Language &lt;br /&gt;• Organization &lt;br /&gt;• Keyword (i.e.”Howto”). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;(There is, in addition, a metadata item called AZList which is used to &lt;br /&gt;determine which bucket of the alphabetic list contains the document’s &lt;br /&gt;title, with values like “A-B” or “C-D-E”. This is used to give precise &lt;br /&gt;control over the divisions in the list. For most other collections it is &lt;br /&gt;absent, and Greenstone assigns the buckets itself.) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If, instead, the user had chosen “New Collection” at this point, she would &lt;br /&gt;have been asked to select what metadata sets should be used in the new &lt;br /&gt;collection. Three standard sets are pre-supplied: Dublin Core, the DLS &lt;br /&gt;metadata set mentioned above, and a set that comprises metadata &lt;br /&gt;elements extracted automatically by Greenstone from the documents in &lt;br /&gt;the collection. The user can also create new metadata sets using a popup &lt;br /&gt;panel activated through the “metadata” menu.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Several different metadata sets can be associated with the same &lt;br /&gt;collection; the system keeps them distinct (so that, for example, &lt;br /&gt;documents can have both a Dublin Core Title and a DLS Title). The &lt;br /&gt;different sets are clearly distinguished in the interface. Behind the scenes, &lt;br /&gt;metadata sets are represented in XML. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assembling the source material &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;After clicking the OK button on the “new collection” popup, the &lt;br /&gt;remaining parts of the interface, which were grayed out before, become &lt;br /&gt;active. The Gather panel, selected by the eponymous tab near the top of &lt;br /&gt;Figure 4, is displayed initially. This allows the user to explore the local &lt;br /&gt;file space and existing collections, gathering up selected documents for &lt;br /&gt;the new collection. The panel is divided into two sections, the left for &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 21 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;browsing existing structures and the right for the documents in the &lt;br /&gt;collection.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Operations available at this stage include: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Navigating the existing file structure hierarchy, and the one being &lt;br /&gt;created, in the usual way. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Dragging and dropping files into the new collection. &lt;br /&gt;• Multiple selection of files. &lt;br /&gt;• Dragging and dropping entire sub-hierarchies. &lt;br /&gt;• Deleting documents from the nascent collection. &lt;br /&gt;• Creating new sub-hierarchies within the collection. &lt;br /&gt;• Filtering the files that are visible, in both the local file system and &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;the collection, based on predetermined groups or on standard file &lt;br /&gt;matching terms. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Invoking the appropriate program to display the contents of a &lt;br /&gt;selected file, by double-clicking it. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Care is taken to deal appropriately with name clashes when files of the &lt;br /&gt;same name in different parts of the computer’s directory structure are &lt;br /&gt;copied into the same folder of the collection. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Figure 5 the user is using the interactive file tree display to explore the &lt;br /&gt;local file system. At this stage, the collection on the right is empty; the &lt;br /&gt;user populates it by dragging and dropping files of interest from the left to &lt;br /&gt;the right panel. Such files are “copied” rather than “moved”: so as not to &lt;br /&gt;disturb the original file system. The usual techniques for multiple &lt;br /&gt;selection, dragging and dropping, structuring the new collection by &lt;br /&gt;creating subdirectories (“folders”), and deleting files from it by moving &lt;br /&gt;them to a trashcan, are all available.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Existing collections are represented by a subdirectory on the left called &lt;br /&gt;“Greenstone Collections,” which can be opened and explored like any &lt;br /&gt;other directory. However, the documents therein differ from ordinary files &lt;br /&gt;because they already have metadata attached, and this is preserved when &lt;br /&gt;they are moved into the new collection. Conflicts may arise because their &lt;br /&gt;metadata may have been assigned using a different metadata set from the &lt;br /&gt;one in use for the new collection, and the user must resolve these. In &lt;br /&gt;Figure 6 the user has selected some documents from an existing collection &lt;br /&gt;and dragged them into the new one. The popup window explains that the &lt;br /&gt;metadata element Organization cannot be automatically imported, and &lt;br /&gt;asks the user to either select a metadata set and press Add to add the &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;22 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;metadata element to that set,1 or choose a metadata set, then an element, &lt;br /&gt;and press Merge to effectively rename the old metadata element to the &lt;br /&gt;new one by merging the two. Metadata in subsequent documents from the &lt;br /&gt;same collection will automatically be handled in the same way. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When large file sets are selected, dragged, and dropped into the new &lt;br /&gt;collection, the copying operation may take some time—particularly if &lt;br /&gt;metadata conversion is involved. To indicate progress, the interface &lt;br /&gt;shows which file is being copied and what percentage of files has been &lt;br /&gt;processed. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Special facilities are provided for dealing with large file sets. For &lt;br /&gt;example, the user can choose to filter the file tree to show only certain &lt;br /&gt;files, using a dropdown menu of file types displayed underneath the trees. &lt;br /&gt;In Figure 7, only the HTM and HTML files are being shown (and only &lt;br /&gt;these files will be copied by drag and drop). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enriching the documents &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next phase in collection building is to enrich the documents by &lt;br /&gt;adding metadata. The Enrich tab brings up a new panel of information &lt;br /&gt;(Figure 8), which shows the document tree representing the collection on &lt;br /&gt;the left and on the right allows metadata to be added to individual &lt;br /&gt;documents, or groups of documents.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Documents that are copied during the first step come with any applicable &lt;br /&gt;metadata attached. If a document is part of a Greenstone collection, &lt;br /&gt;previously defined metadata is carried over to the new collection. Of &lt;br /&gt;course, this new collection may have a different metadata set, or perhaps &lt;br /&gt;just a subset of the defined metadata, and only metadata that pertains to &lt;br /&gt;the new collection’s set is carried over. Resolution of such conflicts may &lt;br /&gt;require user intervention via a supplementary dialog (Figure 6). Any &lt;br /&gt;choices made are remembered for subsequent file copies. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Enrich panel allows metadata values to be assigned to documents in &lt;br /&gt;the collection. For example, new values can be added to the set of existing &lt;br /&gt;values for an element. If the element’s values have a hierarchical &lt;br /&gt;structure, the hierarchy can be extended in the same way. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;                                                 &lt;br /&gt;1 This option is disabled if an element of the same name already exists. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 23 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 6. Importing &lt;br /&gt;existing metadata &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 7. Filtering the &lt;br /&gt;file trees &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;24 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 8. Assigning &lt;br /&gt;metadata using Enrich &lt;br /&gt;view &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 9. Viewing all &lt;br /&gt;metadata for selected &lt;br /&gt;files &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 25 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Metadata values can also be assigned to folders, in just the same way. &lt;br /&gt;Documents in these folders for which this metadata is unspecified inherit &lt;br /&gt;the metadata values. However, they can subsequently be overridden by &lt;br /&gt;supplying different ones for the document itself. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Operations at this stage include: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Assigning new and existing metadata values to documents. &lt;br /&gt;• Assigning metadata to an individual document. &lt;br /&gt;• Assigning metadata to a folder (this is inherited by all documents in &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;the folder, including those in nested folders). &lt;br /&gt;• Assigning hierarchical metadata, whose structure can be &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;dynamically updated if required. &lt;br /&gt;• Editing or updating assigned metadata. &lt;br /&gt;• Reviewing the metadata assigned to a selection of files and &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;directories. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;For our walkthrough example, in Figure 8 the user has selected the folder &lt;br /&gt;ec121e and assigned “EC Courier” as its Organization metadata. The &lt;br /&gt;buttons for updating and removing metadata become active depending on &lt;br /&gt;what selections have been made. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the enrichment phase, or indeed at any other time, the user can &lt;br /&gt;choose to view all the metadata that has been assigned to documents in &lt;br /&gt;the collection. This is done by selecting a set of documents and choosing &lt;br /&gt;Assigned Metadata from the metadata sets menu, which brings up a &lt;br /&gt;popup window like that in Figure 9 that shows the metadata in &lt;br /&gt;spreadsheet form. For large collections it is useful to be able to view the &lt;br /&gt;metadata associated with certain document types only, and if the user has &lt;br /&gt;specified a file filter as mentioned above, only the selected documents are &lt;br /&gt;shown in the metadata display. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The panel in Figure 10 allows the user to edit metadata sets. Here, the &lt;br /&gt;user is looking at the Subject element of the DLS set. The values of this &lt;br /&gt;element form a hierarchy, and the user is examining, and perhaps &lt;br /&gt;changing, the list of values assigned to it. The same panel also allows you &lt;br /&gt;to change the “profile” for mapping elements of one metadata set to &lt;br /&gt;another. This profile is created when importing documents from &lt;br /&gt;collections that have pre-assigned metadata.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;26 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 10. Editing the &lt;br /&gt;metadata set &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 11. Designing &lt;br /&gt;the collection &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 27 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 12. Specifying &lt;br /&gt;which plug-ins to use &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 13. &lt;br /&gt;Configuring &lt;br /&gt;arguments to a plug-in &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;28 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Designing the collection &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Design panel (Figures 11–13) allows one to specify the structure, &lt;br /&gt;organization, and presentation of the collection being created. As noted &lt;br /&gt;earlier, the result of this process is recorded in a “collection configuration &lt;br /&gt;file,” which is Greenstone’s way of expressing the facilities that a &lt;br /&gt;collection requires. This step involves a series of separate interaction &lt;br /&gt;screens, each dealing with one aspect of the collection design. In effect, it &lt;br /&gt;serves as a graphical equivalent to the usual process of editing the &lt;br /&gt;configuration file manually. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Operations include: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Reviewing and editing collection-level metadata such as title, author &lt;br /&gt;and public availability of the collection. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Defining what full-text indexes are to be built. &lt;br /&gt;• Creating sub-collections and having indexes built for them. &lt;br /&gt;• Adding or removing support for predefined interface languages. &lt;br /&gt;• Constructing a list of plug-ins to be used, and their arguments.  &lt;br /&gt;• Presenting the list to the user for review and modification. &lt;br /&gt;• Configuring individual plug-ins. &lt;br /&gt;• Constructing a list of “classifiers,” their arguments, assignment and &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;configuration. &lt;br /&gt;• Assigning formatting strings to various controls within the &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;collection, thus altering its appearance. &lt;br /&gt;• Reviewing the metadata sets, and their elements, used in the &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;collection. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Figure 11 the user has clicked the Design tab and is reviewing the &lt;br /&gt;general information about the collection, entered when the new collection &lt;br /&gt;was created. On the left are listed the various facets that the user can &lt;br /&gt;configure: General, Document Plug-ins, Search Types, Search Indexes, &lt;br /&gt;Partition Indexes, Cross-Collection Search, Browsing Classifiers, Format &lt;br /&gt;Features, Translate Text, Metadata Sets. Appearance and functionality &lt;br /&gt;varies between these. For example, clicking the Plug-in button brings up &lt;br /&gt;the screen shown in Figure 12, which allows you to add, remove or &lt;br /&gt;configure plug-ins, and change the order in which the plug-ins are applied &lt;br /&gt;to documents. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 29 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 14. Getting &lt;br /&gt;ready to create new &lt;br /&gt;collection &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 15. Previewing &lt;br /&gt;the newly built &lt;br /&gt;collection &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;30 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plug-ins and classifiers have many different arguments or “options” that &lt;br /&gt;the user can supply. The dialog box in Figure 13 shows the user &lt;br /&gt;specifying arguments to some of the plug-ins. The grayed-out fields &lt;br /&gt;become active when the user adds the option by clicking the tick-box &lt;br /&gt;beside it. Because Greenstone is a continually growing open-source &lt;br /&gt;system, the number of options tends to increase as developers add new &lt;br /&gt;facilities. To help cope with this, Greenstone has a “plug-in information”  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;utility program that lists the options available for each plug-in, and the &lt;br /&gt;librarian interface automatically invokes this to determine what options to &lt;br /&gt;show. This allows the interactive user interface to automatically keep &lt;br /&gt;pace with developments in the software. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building the collection &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Create panel (Figure 14) is used to construct a collection based on &lt;br /&gt;the documents and assigned metadata. The brunt of this work is borne by &lt;br /&gt;the Greenstone code itself. The user controls this external process through &lt;br /&gt;a series of separate interaction screens, each dealing with the arguments &lt;br /&gt;provided to a certain stage of the creation process. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The user observes the building process though a window that shows not &lt;br /&gt;only the text output generated by Greenstone’s importing and index-&lt;br /&gt;building scripts, but also progress bars that indicate the overall degree of &lt;br /&gt;completion of each script. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 14 shows the Create view. At the top are shown some options that &lt;br /&gt;can be applied during the creation process. The user selects appropriate &lt;br /&gt;values for the options. This figure illustrates a popup “tool tip” that is &lt;br /&gt;available throughout the interface to explain the function of each &lt;br /&gt;argument.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When satisfied with the arguments, the user clicks Build Collection. &lt;br /&gt;Greenstone continually prints text that indicates progress, and this is &lt;br /&gt;shown along with a more informative progress bar. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previewing &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Preview Collection button (Figure 14) is used to view the collection &lt;br /&gt;that has been built. Clicking this button launches a web browser showing &lt;br /&gt;the home page of the collection (Figure 15). In practice, previewing often &lt;br /&gt;shows up deficiencies in the collection design, or in the individual &lt;br /&gt;metadata values, and the user frequently returns to earlier stages to correct &lt;br /&gt;these. This button becomes active once the collection has been created. &lt;br /&gt;The newly created collection will also have been installed on your &lt;br /&gt;Greenstone home page as one of the regular collections. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 31 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Help &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;On-line help is always available, and is invoked using the Help item at the &lt;br /&gt;right of the main menu bar at the top of each of the Figures. This opens up &lt;br /&gt;a hierarchically structured file of help text, and account is taken of the &lt;br /&gt;user’s current context to highlight the section that is appropriate to the &lt;br /&gt;present stage of the interaction. Furthermore, as noted above, whenever &lt;br /&gt;the mouse is held still over any interactive object a small window pops up &lt;br /&gt;to give a textual “tool tip,” as illustrated near the bottom of Figure 14. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;3.2 Librarian Interface user guide &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting Off &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section covers how to create, load, save and delete collections.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Creating a New Collection &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To create a new collection, open the &amp;quot;File&amp;quot; menu and choose &amp;quot;New&amp;quot;. &lt;br /&gt;Several fields need to be filled out -- but you can change their values later &lt;br /&gt;if you need to, in the design view.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Collection title&amp;quot; is the text displayed at the top of your collection's home &lt;br /&gt;page. It can be any length.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Description of content&amp;quot; should describe, in as much detail as possible, &lt;br /&gt;what the collection is about. Use the [Enter] key to break it into &lt;br /&gt;paragraphs.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally you must specify whether the new collection will have the same &lt;br /&gt;appearance and metadata sets as an existing collection, or whether to start &lt;br /&gt;a default &amp;quot;New Collection&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click &amp;quot;OK&amp;quot; to create the collection. If you chose &amp;quot;New Collection&amp;quot; you &lt;br /&gt;are prompted for the metadata sets to use in it. You can choose more than &lt;br /&gt;one, and you can add others later.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clicking &amp;quot;Cancel&amp;quot; returns you to the main screen immediately. Buttons, &lt;br /&gt;like menus, have one character underlined. To &amp;quot;click&amp;quot; the button, press &lt;br /&gt;[ALT] and the underlined character at the same time.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Saving the Collection &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Save your work regularly by opening the &amp;quot;File&amp;quot; menu and choosing &lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;Save&amp;quot;. Saving a collection is not the same as making it ready for use in &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;32 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greenstone (see Producing Your Collection).  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Librarian Interface protects your work by saving it whenever you exit &lt;br /&gt;the program or load another collection. Saved collections are written to a &lt;br /&gt;file named for the collection and with file extension &amp;quot;.col&amp;quot;, located in a &lt;br /&gt;folder of the same name within your Greenstone installation's &amp;quot;collect&amp;quot; &lt;br /&gt;folder.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Opening an Existing Collection &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To open an existing collection, choose &amp;quot;Open&amp;quot; from the &amp;quot;File&amp;quot; menu to &lt;br /&gt;get the Open Collection prompt. A list of your Greenstone collections &lt;br /&gt;appears. Select one to see its description, and click &amp;quot;Open&amp;quot; to load it. If &lt;br /&gt;you seek a collection that resides outside Greenstone's &amp;quot;collect&amp;quot; folder, &lt;br /&gt;click &amp;quot;Browse&amp;quot; for a file system browsing dialog. In case more than one &lt;br /&gt;Greenstone Librarian Interface program is running concurrently, the &lt;br /&gt;relevant directories are &amp;quot;locked&amp;quot; to prevent interference. On opening a &lt;br /&gt;collection, a small temporary lock file is created in its folder. Before &lt;br /&gt;opening a collection, the Librarian Interface checks to ensure that no lock &lt;br /&gt;file already exists. You can tell whether a collection is locked by the &lt;br /&gt;colour of its icon: green for a normal collection, red for a locked one. &lt;br /&gt;However, when the Librarian Interface is exited prematurely the lock file &lt;br /&gt;is sometimes left in place. When you open such a collection, the Librarian &lt;br /&gt;asks if you want to &amp;quot;steal&amp;quot; control of it. Never steal a collection that &lt;br /&gt;someone else is currently working on.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you open a collection that the Greenstone Librarian Interface did &lt;br /&gt;not create, you will be asked to select a metadata set (or sets). If none are &lt;br /&gt;selected, any existing metadata will be ignored. Otherwise, metadata will &lt;br /&gt;be imported just as it is when you drag in files with existing metadata. &lt;br /&gt;The process is described in the Importing Previously Assigned Metadata &lt;br /&gt;section.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deleting Collections &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To permanently delete collections from your Greenstone installation, &lt;br /&gt;choose &amp;quot;Delete...&amp;quot; from the &amp;quot;File&amp;quot; menu. A list of your Greenstone &lt;br /&gt;collections appears. Select one to see its description, then tick the box at &lt;br /&gt;the bottom of the dialog and click &amp;quot;Delete&amp;quot; to delete the collection. This &lt;br /&gt;action is irreversible, so check carefully that you no longer need the &lt;br /&gt;collection before proceeding!  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Downloading Files From the Internet &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;Download&amp;quot; view helps you download resources from the internet. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 33 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section explains the Librarian Interface's mirroring process.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Download view &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section describes how to configure a download task and control the &lt;br /&gt;downloading process.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Access the &amp;quot;Download&amp;quot; view by clicking its tab. The top half of the &lt;br /&gt;screen shows the downloading controls. The bottom half is initially &lt;br /&gt;empty, but will show a list of pending and completed downloading jobs.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Files are downloaded into a folder in the workspace called &amp;quot;Downloaded &lt;br /&gt;Files&amp;quot; (only present when mirroring is enabled), and can be used in all &lt;br /&gt;collections built with the Librarian Interface. Files in this area are named &lt;br /&gt;by their full web URL. A new folder is created for each host, followed by &lt;br /&gt;others for each part of the path. This ensures that each file is distinct.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use the first of the download configuration controls, &amp;quot;Source URL&amp;quot;, to &lt;br /&gt;enter the URL of a target resource. Use the &amp;quot;Download Depth&amp;quot; control to &lt;br /&gt;limit how many hyperlinks to follow when downloading: Set this to 0 to &lt;br /&gt;download a single web page; set it to 1 to download a page and all the &lt;br /&gt;pages it points to. The depth limit is ignored when downloading media &lt;br /&gt;other than html pages. Next, there are several checkbox controls which &lt;br /&gt;can be set to turn on the specified feature for a specific download. Once &lt;br /&gt;the configuration is set up, click &amp;quot;Download&amp;quot; to start the new download &lt;br /&gt;job. There are two other button controls: &amp;quot;Preferences&amp;quot;, which links to the &lt;br /&gt;connection section of the Preferences where proxy settings can be edited; &lt;br /&gt;and &amp;quot;Clear Cache&amp;quot;, which deletes all previously downloaded files.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The download list has an entry for each web page download. Each entry &lt;br /&gt;has a text region that gives details of the task along with a progress bar &lt;br /&gt;showing current activity. Three buttons appear to the left of each entry. &lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;Pause&amp;quot; is used for pausing a currently downloading task. &amp;quot;View Log&amp;quot; &lt;br /&gt;opens a window showing the download log file. &amp;quot;Close&amp;quot; terminates the &lt;br /&gt;download and removes the task from the list. The Preferences section &lt;br /&gt;describes how to establish an Internet connection via a proxy. If &lt;br /&gt;authentication is needed, the proxy server prompts for identification and &lt;br /&gt;password. The Librarian Interface does not store passwords between &lt;br /&gt;sessions.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collecting Files for Your Collection &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once you have a new collection you need to get some files into it. These &lt;br /&gt;may come from your ordinary file space, or from other Greenstone &lt;br /&gt;collections. Some may already have attached metadata. This section &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;34 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;describes how to import files.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Gather View &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section introduces the Gather area that you use to select what files to &lt;br /&gt;include in the collection you are building.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Librarian Interface starts with the Gather view. To return to this view &lt;br /&gt;later, click the &amp;quot;Gather&amp;quot; tab directly below the menu bar.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The two large areas titled &amp;quot;Workspace&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Collection&amp;quot; are used to move &lt;br /&gt;files into your collection. They contain &amp;quot;file trees&amp;quot;, graphical structures &lt;br /&gt;that represent files and folders.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Select an item in the tree by clicking it. (There are other ways; see &lt;br /&gt;below.) Double-click a folder, or single-click the switch symbol beside it, &lt;br /&gt;to expand (or collapse) its contents. Double-click a file to open it using its &lt;br /&gt;associated application program (see File Associations).  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Workspace file tree shows the sources of data available to the &lt;br /&gt;Librarian Interface -- the local file system (including disk and CD-ROM &lt;br /&gt;drives), the contents of existing Greenstone collections, and the cache of &lt;br /&gt;downloaded files if Web mirroring is enabled. You can copy and view &lt;br /&gt;these files but you cannot move, delete, or edit them, with the exception &lt;br /&gt;of the downloaded files, which can be deleted. Navigate this space to find &lt;br /&gt;the files you want to include in the collection.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Collection file tree represents the contents of the collection so far. &lt;br /&gt;Initially, it is empty.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can resize the spaces by mousing over the grey bar that separates the &lt;br /&gt;trees (the shape of the pointer changes) and dragging.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the bottom of the window is a status area that shows the progress of &lt;br /&gt;actions involving files (copying, moving and deleting). These can take &lt;br /&gt;some time to complete. The &amp;quot;Stop&amp;quot; button stops any action that is &lt;br /&gt;currently in progress.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two large buttons occupy the lower right corner of the screen. &amp;quot;New &lt;br /&gt;Folder&amp;quot;, with a picture of a folder, creates new folders (see Creating &lt;br /&gt;folders). &amp;quot;Delete&amp;quot;, with a garbage can, removes files. Clicking the Delete &lt;br /&gt;button will remove any selected files from the Collection file tree. &lt;br /&gt;Alternatively, files can be deleted by dragging them onto the Delete &lt;br /&gt;button. To select several sequential items, select the first and then hold &lt;br /&gt;down [Shift] and click on the last -- the selection will encompass all &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 35 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;intervening items. Select non-sequential files by holding down [Ctrl] &lt;br /&gt;while clicking. Use these two methods together to select groups of non-&lt;br /&gt;adjacent items.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Certain folders -- such as the one containing your own web pages -- &lt;br /&gt;sometimes have special significance. The Librarian Interface can map &lt;br /&gt;such folders to the first level of the file tree. To do this, right-click the &lt;br /&gt;desired folder. Select &amp;quot;Create Shortcut&amp;quot;, and enter a name for the folder. &lt;br /&gt;To remove an item, right-click the mapped folder and select &amp;quot;Remove &lt;br /&gt;Shortcut&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Creating Folders &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use folders in the Collection file tree to group files together and make &lt;br /&gt;them easier to find. Folders can be placed inside folders. There is virtually &lt;br /&gt;no limit to how many folders you can have or how deeply they can be &lt;br /&gt;nested.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To create a new folder, optionally select an existing folder in the &lt;br /&gt;Collection Tree and click the New Folder button. The new folder appears &lt;br /&gt;within the selected one, or at the top level if none is selected. You are &lt;br /&gt;prompted for the folder's name (default &amp;quot;New Folder&amp;quot;).  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Folders can also be created by right-clicking over a folder, choosing &lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;New Folder&amp;quot; and proceeding as above.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adding Files &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Files can be copied into the collection by dragging and dropping. The &lt;br /&gt;mouse pointer becomes a ghost of the selected item (or, if more than one &lt;br /&gt;is selected, the number of them). Drop the selection into the Collection &lt;br /&gt;Tree to copy the files there (if the source was the Workspace Tree) or &lt;br /&gt;move them around within the collection (if the source was the Collection &lt;br /&gt;Tree).  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When copying multiple files, they are all placed in the target folder at the &lt;br /&gt;same level, irrespective of the folder structure they occupied originally. &lt;br /&gt;When you copy a second file with the same name into the same folder, &lt;br /&gt;you are asked whether to overwrite the first one. Respond &amp;quot;No&amp;quot; and the &lt;br /&gt;file will not be copied, but the others will be. To cancel all remaining &lt;br /&gt;copy actions, click the &amp;quot;stop&amp;quot; button.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Only the &amp;quot;highest&amp;quot; items in a selection are moved. A folder is higher than &lt;br /&gt;its children. You cannot select files within a folder and also the folder &lt;br /&gt;itself. When you add a file, the Librarian Interface searches through the &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;36 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;source folders for auxiliary files containing metadata previously assigned &lt;br /&gt;to the added file and, if it finds one, begins to import this metadata. As the &lt;br /&gt;operation proceeds, you may be prompted (perhaps several times) for &lt;br /&gt;extra information to match the imported metadata to the metadata sets in &lt;br /&gt;your collection. This process involves many different prompts, described &lt;br /&gt;in the Importing Previously Assigned Metadata section. For a more &lt;br /&gt;detailed explanation of associating metadata with files read Chapter 2 of &lt;br /&gt;the Greenstone Developer's Guide -- Getting the most out of your &lt;br /&gt;documents.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Removing Files &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are several methods for removing files and folders. You must first &lt;br /&gt;indicate what items to remove by selecting one or more files and folders &lt;br /&gt;as described in The Gather View.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once files have been selected, click the &amp;quot;delete&amp;quot; button to remove them, &lt;br /&gt;or press the [Delete] key on your keyboard, or drag them from the &lt;br /&gt;collection to the delete button and drop them there.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Filtering the Tree &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Filtering&amp;quot; the collection tree allows you to narrow down the search for &lt;br /&gt;particular files.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;Show Files&amp;quot; pull-down menu underneath each tree shows a list of &lt;br /&gt;predefined filters, such as &amp;quot;Images&amp;quot;. Choosing this temporarily hides all &lt;br /&gt;other files in the tree. To restore the tree, change the filter back to &amp;quot;All &lt;br /&gt;Files&amp;quot;. These operations do not alter the collection, nor do they affect the &lt;br /&gt;folders in the tree. You can specify a custom filter by typing in a pattern &lt;br /&gt;to match files against. Use standard file system abbreviations such as &lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;*.*&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;*.doc&amp;quot; (&amp;quot;*&amp;quot; matches any characters).  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enriching the Collection with Metadata &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having gathered several files into the collection, now enrich them with &lt;br /&gt;additional information called &amp;quot;metadata&amp;quot;. This section explains how &lt;br /&gt;metadata is created, edited, assigned and retrieved, and how to use &lt;br /&gt;external metadata sources (also see Chapter 2 of the Greenstone &lt;br /&gt;Developer's Guide -- Getting the most out of your documents).  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Enrich View &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use the Enrich view to assign metadata to the documents in the &lt;br /&gt;collection. Metadata is data about data -- typically title, author, creation &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 37 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;date, and so on. Each metadata item has two parts: &amp;quot;element&amp;quot; tells what &lt;br /&gt;kind of item it is (such as author), and &amp;quot;value&amp;quot; gives the value of that &lt;br /&gt;metadata element (such as the author's name).  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the left of the &amp;quot;Enrich&amp;quot; view is the Collection Tree. To the right is the &lt;br /&gt;Metadata Table, which shows metadata for any selected files or folders in &lt;br /&gt;the Collection Tree. Columns are named in grey at the top, and can be &lt;br /&gt;resized by dragging the separating line. Clicking any row transfers its &lt;br /&gt;details to the metadata editing controls below. If several files are selected, &lt;br /&gt;black text indicates that the value is common to all of the selected files, &lt;br /&gt;while grey text indicates that it is not. Black values may be updated or &lt;br /&gt;removed, while grey ones can be removed from those that have it, or &lt;br /&gt;appended to the others.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A folder icon may appear beside some metadata entries. This indicates &lt;br /&gt;that the values are inherited from a parent (or ancestor) folder. Inherited &lt;br /&gt;metadata cannot be edited or removed, only appended to or overwritten. &lt;br /&gt;Click on the folder icon to go immediately to the folder where the &lt;br /&gt;metadata is assigned.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The metadata editing controls at the lower right appear only when a file is &lt;br /&gt;selected from the tree and a row is selected from the table. Use them to &lt;br /&gt;update, append, and remove the metadata value. The value field is for &lt;br /&gt;entering or editing the metadata value. Beside it is a button labelled &amp;quot;...&amp;quot; &lt;br /&gt;which, when clicked, opens a larger editing box. In the buttons below, &lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;Append&amp;quot; assigns the value as new metadata and adds it to any existing &lt;br /&gt;values for the selected element, &amp;quot;Replace&amp;quot; overwrites the selected existing &lt;br /&gt;value with the new one, and &amp;quot;Remove&amp;quot; clears the selected value. &lt;br /&gt;Underneath, labelled &amp;quot;All Previous Values&amp;quot;, is the &amp;quot;Value Tree&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Value Tree expands and collapses. Usually it is a list that shows all &lt;br /&gt;values entered previously for the selected element. Clicking an entry &lt;br /&gt;automatically places it into the value field. Conversely, typing in the text &lt;br /&gt;field selects the Value Tree entry that starts with the characters you have &lt;br /&gt;typed. Pressing [Tab] auto-completes the typing with the selected value.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Metadata values can be organised into a hierarchy. This is shown in the &lt;br /&gt;Value Tree using folders for internal levels. Hierarchical values can be &lt;br /&gt;entered using the character &amp;quot;|&amp;quot; to separate the levels. For example, &lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;Cards|Red|Diamonds|Seven&amp;quot; might be used in a hierarchy that represents &lt;br /&gt;a pack of playing cards. This enables values to be grouped together. &lt;br /&gt;Groups can also be assigned as metadata to files.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greenstone extracts metadata automatically from documents into a &lt;br /&gt;metadata set whose elements are prefixed by &amp;quot;ex.&amp;quot;. This has no value tree &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;38 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;and cannot be edited, so the edit controls are hidden if such an entry is &lt;br /&gt;selected. The &amp;quot;...&amp;quot; button still serves to expand the value, but the text &lt;br /&gt;cannot be edited.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Selecting Metadata Sets &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sets of predefined metadata elements are known as &amp;quot;metadata sets&amp;quot;. An &lt;br /&gt;example is the Dublin Core metadata set. When you add a metadata set to &lt;br /&gt;your collection, its elements become available for selection. You can have &lt;br /&gt;more than one set; to prevent name clashes a short identifier that &lt;br /&gt;identifies the metadata set is pre-pended to the element name. For &lt;br /&gt;instance the Dublin Core element Creator becomes &amp;quot;dc.Creator&amp;quot;. &lt;br /&gt;Metadata sets are stored in the Librarian Interface's metadata folder and &lt;br /&gt;have the suffix &amp;quot;.mds&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To control the metadata sets used in a collection, use the &amp;quot;Metadata Sets&amp;quot; &lt;br /&gt;entry on the Design view.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Appending New Metadata &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;We now add a metadata item -- both element and value -- to a file. First &lt;br /&gt;select the file from the Collection file tree on the left. The action causes &lt;br /&gt;any metadata previously assigned to this file to appear in the table at the &lt;br /&gt;right.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next select the metadata element you want to add by clicking its row in &lt;br /&gt;the table.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Type the value into the value field. Do not use the character &amp;quot;|&amp;quot;, as it is &lt;br /&gt;used for constructing hierarchies. When finished, click &amp;quot;Append&amp;quot; to add &lt;br /&gt;the new value as metadata for the chosen file. The value immediately &lt;br /&gt;appears in the Metadata table.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can also add metadata to a folder, or to several multiply selected files &lt;br /&gt;at once. It is added to all files within the folder or selection, and to child &lt;br /&gt;folders. Keep in mind that if you assign metadata to a folder, any new &lt;br /&gt;files in it automatically inherit the folder's values.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you choose metadata that occurs in some of the selected files and click &lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;Append&amp;quot;, it is added to the other files in the selection too. You can add &lt;br /&gt;structure to metadata values by using paths as described in The Enrich &lt;br /&gt;View.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 39 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adding Previously Defined Metadata &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To add metadata that has an existing value, first select the file, then select &lt;br /&gt;the required value from the value tree, expanding hierarchy folders as &lt;br /&gt;necessary. The value of the selected entry automatically appears in the &lt;br /&gt;Value text field (alternatively, use the value tree's auto-select and auto-&lt;br /&gt;complete features). Click &amp;quot;Append&amp;quot; to add the metadata to the selected &lt;br /&gt;file.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The process of adding metadata with already-existing values to folders or &lt;br /&gt;multiple files is just the same.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Updating Metadata &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To update the value of a piece of metadata, first choose the file to which &lt;br /&gt;that value applies, and then the metadata element whose value you want &lt;br /&gt;to change. Your selection appears in the metadata edit controls. Edit the &lt;br /&gt;value field and click &amp;quot;Replace&amp;quot; to alter the metadata.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The process is the same when updating a folder with child folders or &lt;br /&gt;multiple files, but you can only update metadata that is common to all &lt;br /&gt;files/folders selected.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The value tree shows all previous values, not just those currently &lt;br /&gt;assigned. Thus the value you have replaced will remain in the value tree.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Removing Metadata &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;You remove metadata the same way as you update it. First select a file &lt;br /&gt;from the file tree, then use the metadata table to select the metadata. If the &lt;br /&gt;metadata has a value assigned, the &amp;quot;Remove&amp;quot; button becomes active. &lt;br /&gt;Click it to remove the metadata from the specified file. Other files remain &lt;br /&gt;unchanged, and the value remains in the Value Tree.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Removing metadata from folders or multiple files works the same way.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reviewing Assigned Metadata &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you need to see the metadata assigned to many or all files at &lt;br /&gt;once -- for instance, to determine how many files are left to work on, or to &lt;br /&gt;get some idea of the spread of dates.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Select the files you wish to examine, then right-click and choose &lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;Assigned Metadata...&amp;quot;. A window called &amp;quot;All Metadata&amp;quot;, dominated by a &lt;br /&gt;large table with many columns, appears. The first column shows file &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;40 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;names; the rows show all metadata values assigned to those files.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Drawing the table can take some time if many files are selected. You can &lt;br /&gt;continue to use the Librarian Interface while the &amp;quot;All Metadata&amp;quot; window &lt;br /&gt;is open.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click &amp;quot;Close&amp;quot; to hide the window. You can also view the &amp;quot;All Metadata&amp;quot; &lt;br /&gt;table by selecting the files you wish to examine, right-clicking, and &lt;br /&gt;choosing &amp;quot;Assigned Metadata...&amp;quot;. If a folder has been selected, all its child &lt;br /&gt;files are included in the table.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it gets too large, you can filter the &amp;quot;All Metadata&amp;quot; table by applying &lt;br /&gt;filters to the columns. As new filters are added, only those rows that &lt;br /&gt;match them remain visible. To set, modify or clear a filter, click on the &lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;funnel&amp;quot; icon at the top of a column. You are prompted for information &lt;br /&gt;about the filter. Once a filter is set, the column header changes colour.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The prompt has a &amp;quot;Simple&amp;quot; and an &amp;quot;Advanced&amp;quot; tab. The Simple version &lt;br /&gt;filters columns so that they only show rows that contain a certain &lt;br /&gt;metadata value (&amp;quot;*&amp;quot; matches all values). You can select metadata values &lt;br /&gt;from the pull-down list. The Advanced version allows different matching &lt;br /&gt;operations: must start with, does not contain, alphabetically less than and &lt;br /&gt;is equal to. The value to be matched can be edited to be any string &lt;br /&gt;(including &amp;quot;*&amp;quot;), and you can choose whether the matching should be case &lt;br /&gt;insensitive. Finally, you can specify a second matching condition that you &lt;br /&gt;can use to specify a range of values (by selecting AND) or alternative &lt;br /&gt;values (by selecting OR). Below this area is a box that allows you to &lt;br /&gt;change the sort order (ascending or descending). Once you have finished, &lt;br /&gt;click &amp;quot;Set Filter&amp;quot; to apply the new filter to the column. Click &amp;quot;Clear &lt;br /&gt;Filter&amp;quot; to remove a current filter. Note that the filter details are retained &lt;br /&gt;even when the filter is cleared.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, to sort the &amp;quot;All Metadata&amp;quot; table, choose a column, select the &lt;br /&gt;default filter setting (a Simple filter on &amp;quot;*&amp;quot;), and choose ascending or &lt;br /&gt;descending ordering.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Importing Previously Assigned Metadata &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section describes how to import previously assigned metadata: &lt;br /&gt;metadata assigned to documents before they were added to the collection.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If metadata in a form recognized by the Librarian Interface has been &lt;br /&gt;previously assigned to a file -- for example, when you choose documents &lt;br /&gt;from an existing Greenstone collection -- it is imported automatically &lt;br /&gt;when you add the file. To do this, the metadata must be mapped to the &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 41 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;metadata sets available in the collection.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Librarian Interface prompts for the necessary information. The &lt;br /&gt;prompt gives brief instructions and then shows the name of the metadata &lt;br /&gt;element that is being imported, just as it appears in the source file. This &lt;br /&gt;field cannot be edited or changed. Next you choose what metadata set the &lt;br /&gt;new element should map to, and then the appropriate metadata element in &lt;br /&gt;that set. The system automatically selects the closest match, in terms of &lt;br /&gt;set and element, for the new metadata.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having checked the mapping, you can choose &amp;quot;Add&amp;quot; to add the new &lt;br /&gt;metadata element to the chosen metadata set. (This is only enabled if &lt;br /&gt;there is no element of the same name within the chosen set.) &amp;quot;Replace&amp;quot; &lt;br /&gt;maps the new element to the one chosen by the user. Finally, &amp;quot;Ignore&amp;quot; &lt;br /&gt;does not import any metadata with this element name. Once you have &lt;br /&gt;specified how to import a certain piece of metadata, the mapping &lt;br /&gt;information is retained for the collection's lifetime.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;For details on the metadata.xml files which Greenstone uses to store the &lt;br /&gt;metadata, see Chapter 2 of the Greenstone Developer's Guide -- Getting &lt;br /&gt;the most out of your documents.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Designing Your Collection's Appearance &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once your files are marked up with metadata, you next decide how it &lt;br /&gt;should appear to users as a Greenstone collection. What kind of &lt;br /&gt;information is searchable? What ways are provided to browse through the &lt;br /&gt;documents? What languages are supported? Where do the buttons appear &lt;br /&gt;on the page? These things can be customized; this section describes how &lt;br /&gt;to do it.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Design View &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section introduces you to the design view and explains how to &lt;br /&gt;navigate between the various views within this pane.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the Librarian Interface, you can configure how the collection &lt;br /&gt;appears to the user. The configuration options are divided into different &lt;br /&gt;sections, each associated with a particular stage of navigating or &lt;br /&gt;presenting information.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the left is a list of different views, and on the right are the controls &lt;br /&gt;associated with the current one. To change to a different view, click its &lt;br /&gt;name in the list.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;42 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To understand the stages and terms involved in designing a collection, &lt;br /&gt;first read Chapters 1 and 2 of the Greenstone Developer's Guide.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;General Settings &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section explains how to review and alter the general settings &lt;br /&gt;associated with your collection. First, under &amp;quot;Design Sections&amp;quot;, click &lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;General&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here the values provided during collection creation can be modified.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the top of the page is an instruction box, which appears for each of the &lt;br /&gt;different sections. It contains a brief list of instructions to remind you &lt;br /&gt;what functionality is available.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;First are the contact emails of the collection's creator and maintainer. The &lt;br /&gt;following field allows you to change the collection title. The folder that &lt;br /&gt;the collection is stored in is shown next, but this cannot be edited. The &lt;br /&gt;next one specifies (in the form of a URL) the icon to show at the top left &lt;br /&gt;of the collection's &amp;quot;About&amp;quot; page, and the next is the icon used in the &lt;br /&gt;Greenstone library page to link to the collection. Then, a checkbox &lt;br /&gt;controls whether the collection should be publicly accessible. Finally &lt;br /&gt;comes the &amp;quot;Collection Description&amp;quot; text area as described in Creating A &lt;br /&gt;New Collection.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Document Plugins &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section describes how to configure the document plugins the &lt;br /&gt;collection uses. It explains how you specify what plugins to use, what &lt;br /&gt;parameters to pass to them, and in what order they occur. Under &amp;quot;Design &lt;br /&gt;Sections&amp;quot;, click &amp;quot;Document Plugins&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To add a plugin, select it using the &amp;quot;Select plugin to add&amp;quot; pull-down list &lt;br /&gt;near the bottom and then click &amp;quot;Add Plugin&amp;quot;. A window appears entitled &lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;Configuring Arguments&amp;quot;; it is described later. Once you have configured &lt;br /&gt;the new plugin, it is added to the end of the &amp;quot;Currently Assigned Plugins&amp;quot; &lt;br /&gt;list. Note that, except for UnknownPlug, each plugin may only occur once &lt;br /&gt;in the list.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To remove a plugin, select it in the list and click &amp;quot;Remove Plugin&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plugins are configured by providing arguments. To alter them, select the &lt;br /&gt;plugin from the list and click &amp;quot;Configure Plugin&amp;quot; (or double-click the &lt;br /&gt;plugin). A &amp;quot;Configuring Arguments&amp;quot; dialog appears with various controls &lt;br /&gt;for specifying arguments.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 43 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are different kinds of controls. Some are checkboxes, and clicking &lt;br /&gt;one adds the appropriate option to the plugin. Others are text strings, with &lt;br /&gt;a checkbox and a text field. Click the box to enable the argument, then &lt;br /&gt;type appropriate text (regular expression, file path etc) in the box. Others &lt;br /&gt;are pull-down menus from which you can select from a given set of &lt;br /&gt;values. To learn what an argument does, let the mouse hover over its &lt;br /&gt;name for a moment and a description will appear.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you have changed the configuration, click &amp;quot;OK&amp;quot; to commit the &lt;br /&gt;changes and close the dialog, or &amp;quot;Cancel&amp;quot; to close the dialog without &lt;br /&gt;changing any plugin arguments.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The plugins in the list are executed in order, and the ordering is &lt;br /&gt;sometimes important. Two plugins, ArcPlug and RecPlug, are vital to the &lt;br /&gt;collection building process, and are fixed in place at the end of the list &lt;br /&gt;(with a separator line). To change the ordering of the other ones, select &lt;br /&gt;the plugin you want to move and click &amp;quot;Move Up&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;Move Down&amp;quot;. The &lt;br /&gt;Librarian Interface does its best to determine what arguments a plugin &lt;br /&gt;supports. However, there may be cases where the user wants to specify &lt;br /&gt;special arguments, and for this a text field called &amp;quot;Custom Arguments&amp;quot; (at &lt;br /&gt;the bottom) is provided. Any text in it is appended verbatim to the end of &lt;br /&gt;the plugin command.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Search Types &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section explains how to modify a new design feature in Greenstone, &lt;br /&gt;Search Types, which allow fielded searching. Under &amp;quot;Design Sections&amp;quot;, &lt;br /&gt;click &amp;quot;Search Types&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you enter the Search Types view, first check &amp;quot;Enable Advanced &lt;br /&gt;Searches&amp;quot;, which activates the other controls. This migrates the collection &lt;br /&gt;to Greenstone 2.4 format, which supports fielded searching, and means &lt;br /&gt;that (a) the index design is different (explained in the Search Indexes &lt;br /&gt;section), (b) there are more text fragments to translate (see Translation), &lt;br /&gt;and (c) the collection will not be usable under older Greenstone &lt;br /&gt;installations. If you later uncheck this field, most of your collection will &lt;br /&gt;be migrated back to Greenstone 2.39. However the Librarian Interface &lt;br /&gt;cannot convert the new index specifications into older ones, so you will &lt;br /&gt;have to re-enter them manually.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To add a search type, select it from the &amp;quot;Search Types&amp;quot; list and click &amp;quot;Add &lt;br /&gt;Search Type&amp;quot;. Each type can only appear in the list once.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To remove a search type, select it from the &amp;quot;Currently Assigned Search &lt;br /&gt;Types&amp;quot; list and click &amp;quot;Remove Search Type&amp;quot;. The list must contain at &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;44 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;least one search type.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To change to order of a search type, select it from the list and click &amp;quot;Move &lt;br /&gt;Up&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;Move Down&amp;quot;. The first one will be the default.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Search Indexes &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indexes specify what parts of the collection are searchable. This section &lt;br /&gt;explains how to add and remove indexes, and set a default index. Under &lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;Design Sections&amp;quot;, click &amp;quot;Search Indexes&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To add an index, type a name for it into the &amp;quot;Index Name&amp;quot; field. Select &lt;br /&gt;which of the possible information sources to index by clicking the &lt;br /&gt;checkboxes beside them. The list shows all the assigned metadata &lt;br /&gt;elements, as well the full text. Having selected the data sources, choose &lt;br /&gt;the granularity of the index, using the &amp;quot;At the level&amp;quot; menu. Once these &lt;br /&gt;details are complete, &amp;quot;Add Index&amp;quot; becomes active (unless there is an &lt;br /&gt;existing index with the same settings). Click it to add the new index.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To edit an index, select it and change the index details, then click &lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;Replace Index&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To remove an index, select it from the list of assigned indexes and click &lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;Remove Index&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The default index, the one used on the collection's search page, is tagged &lt;br /&gt;with &amp;quot;[Default Index]&amp;quot; in the &amp;quot;Assigned Indexes&amp;quot; list. To set it, select an &lt;br /&gt;index from the list and click &amp;quot;Set Default&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If advanced searching is enabled (via the Search Types view), the index &lt;br /&gt;controls are different. Each index is based on just one data source. There &lt;br /&gt;is a new pseudo-data source &amp;quot;allfields&amp;quot; which provides searching across &lt;br /&gt;all specified indexes at once. Levels are not assigned to a specific index, &lt;br /&gt;but apply across all indexes: thus indexes and levels are added separately. &lt;br /&gt;Indexes are removed in the same way as above, but the default index can &lt;br /&gt;no longer be set -- it is simply the first index assigned.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To create indexes on all sources, click the &amp;quot;Add All&amp;quot; button. The name of &lt;br /&gt;each index will default to the source name. To change the name, select an &lt;br /&gt;index, change its details, and click &amp;quot;Replace Index&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Partition Indexes &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indexes are built on particular text or metadata sources. The search space &lt;br /&gt;can be further controlled by partitioning the index, either by language or &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 45 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;by a predetermined filter. This section describes how to do this. Under &lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;Design Sections&amp;quot;, click &amp;quot;Partition Indexes&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;Partition Indexes&amp;quot; view has three tabs; &amp;quot;Define Filters&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Assign &lt;br /&gt;Partitions&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Assign Languages&amp;quot;. To learn more about partitions read &lt;br /&gt;about subcollections and subindexes in Chapter 2 of the Greenstone &lt;br /&gt;Developer's Guide.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Define Filters &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Filters allows you to group together into a subcollection all documents in &lt;br /&gt;an index for which a metadata value matches a given pattern.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To create a filter, click the &amp;quot;Define Filters&amp;quot; tab and enter a name for the &lt;br /&gt;new filter into the &amp;quot;Name the subcollection filter&amp;quot; field. Next choose a &lt;br /&gt;document attribute to match against, either a metadata element or the &lt;br /&gt;name of the file in question. Enter a regular expression to use during the &lt;br /&gt;matching. You can toggle between &amp;quot;Including&amp;quot; documents that match the &lt;br /&gt;filter, or &amp;quot;Excluding&amp;quot; them. Finally, you can specify any of the standard &lt;br /&gt;PERL regular expression flags to use when matching (e.g. &amp;quot;i&amp;quot; for case-&lt;br /&gt;insensitive matching). Finally, click &amp;quot;Add Filter&amp;quot; to add the filter to the &lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;Defined Subcollection Filters&amp;quot; list.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To remove a filter, select it from the list and click &amp;quot;Remove Filter&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To alter a filter, select it from the list, change any of the values that &lt;br /&gt;appear in the editing controls and click &amp;quot;Replace Filter&amp;quot; to commit the &lt;br /&gt;changes.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assign Partitions &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having defined a subcollection filter, use the &amp;quot;Assign Partitions&amp;quot; tab to &lt;br /&gt;build indexes for it (or for a group of filters). Select the desired filter (or &lt;br /&gt;filters) from the &amp;quot;Defined Subcollection Filters&amp;quot; list, enter a name for your &lt;br /&gt;partition in the &amp;quot;Partition Name&amp;quot; field, and click &amp;quot;Add Partition&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To remove a partition, select it from the list and click &amp;quot;Remove Partition&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To make a partition the default one, select it from the list and click &amp;quot;Set &lt;br /&gt;Default&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To clear the default partition, click &amp;quot;Clear Default&amp;quot;.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;46 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assign Languages &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section details how to restrict search indexes to particular languages. &lt;br /&gt;You do this by generating a partition using the &amp;quot;Assign Languages&amp;quot; tab of &lt;br /&gt;the &amp;quot;Partition Indexes&amp;quot; view.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To add a new language to partition by, use the &amp;quot;Assign Languages&amp;quot; tab to &lt;br /&gt;build an index for it. Select the desired language from the &amp;quot;Language to &lt;br /&gt;add&amp;quot; pull-down list and click &amp;quot;Add Language&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To remove a language, select it from the &amp;quot;Language Selection&amp;quot; list and &lt;br /&gt;click &amp;quot;Remove Language&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To set the default language, select it from the list and click &amp;quot;Set Default&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To clear the default language, click &amp;quot;Clear Default&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cross-Collection Searching &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greenstone can search across several different collections as though they &lt;br /&gt;were one. This is done by creating a &amp;quot;super-collection&amp;quot; that comprises the &lt;br /&gt;individual collections. Under &amp;quot;Design Sections&amp;quot;, click &amp;quot;Cross-Collection &lt;br /&gt;Search&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Cross-Collection Search view shows a checklist of available &lt;br /&gt;collections. The current collection is ticked and cannot be deselected. To &lt;br /&gt;add another collection to be searched in parallel, click it in the list (click &lt;br /&gt;again to remove it). If only one collection is selected, there is no cross-&lt;br /&gt;collection searching.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;For further details, see Chapter 1 of the Greenstone Developer's Guide.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Classifiers &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section explains how to assign &amp;quot;classifiers&amp;quot;, which are used for &lt;br /&gt;browsing, to the collection. Under &amp;quot;Design Sections&amp;quot;, click &amp;quot;Browsing &lt;br /&gt;Classifiers&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To add a classifier, select it using the &amp;quot;Select classifier to add&amp;quot; pull-down &lt;br /&gt;list near the bottom and then click &amp;quot;Add Specified Classifier&amp;quot;. A window &lt;br /&gt;appears entitled &amp;quot;Configuring Arguments&amp;quot;; instructions for this dialog are &lt;br /&gt;just the same as for plugins (see Document Plugins). Once you have &lt;br /&gt;configured the new classifier, it is added to the end of the &amp;quot;Currently &lt;br /&gt;Assigned Classifiers&amp;quot; list.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 47 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To remove a classifier, select it from the list and click &amp;quot;Remove Selected &lt;br /&gt;Classifier&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To change the arguments a classifier, select it from the list and click &lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;Configure Selected Classifier&amp;quot; (or double-click on the classifier in the &lt;br /&gt;list).  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ordering of classifiers in the collection's navigation bar is reflected in &lt;br /&gt;their order here. To change it, select the classifier you want to move and &lt;br /&gt;click &amp;quot;Move Up&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;Move Down&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;For further information on classifiers read Chapter 2, Greenstone &lt;br /&gt;Developer's Guide -- Getting the most out of your documents.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Format Features &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Format commands control the structure and appearance of the collection. &lt;br /&gt;They affect such things as where buttons appear when a document is &lt;br /&gt;shown, and what links are displayed by the DateList classifier. Format &lt;br /&gt;commands are not easy to develop, and you should read Chapter 2 of the &lt;br /&gt;Greenstone Developer's Guide. This section discusses the format settings, &lt;br /&gt;and how the Librarian Interface gives access to them. Under &amp;quot;Design &lt;br /&gt;Sections&amp;quot;, click &amp;quot;Format Features&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can apply a format command to anything in the &amp;quot;Choose Feature&amp;quot; &lt;br /&gt;pull-down list, which includes each classifier and a predefined list of &lt;br /&gt;features. When you select a feature, there are two types of control. Some &lt;br /&gt;features are simply enabled or disabled, and this is controlled by a &lt;br /&gt;checkbox. Others require a format string to be specified. For these there is &lt;br /&gt;a pull-down list (&amp;quot;Affected Component&amp;quot;) for selecting which part of the &lt;br /&gt;feature the string applies to (if necessary), a text area (&amp;quot;HTML Format &lt;br /&gt;String&amp;quot;) for entering the string, and a selection of predefined &amp;quot;Variables&amp;quot;. &lt;br /&gt;To insert a variable into the current position in the format string, select it &lt;br /&gt;from the pull-down list and click &amp;quot;Insert&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can specify a default format for a particular component by selecting &lt;br /&gt;the blank feature. This format is then applied to all applicable features &lt;br /&gt;unless otherwise specified.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To add a new format command, fill out the information as explained &lt;br /&gt;above and click &amp;quot;Add Format&amp;quot;. The new format command appears in the &lt;br /&gt;list of &amp;quot;Currently Assigned Format Commands&amp;quot;. Only one format &lt;br /&gt;command can be assigned to each feature/component combination.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To remove a format command, select it from the list and click &amp;quot;Remove &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;48 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Format&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To change a format command, select it from the list, modify the settings, &lt;br /&gt;and click &amp;quot;Replace Format&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;For more information about variables and the feature components, read &lt;br /&gt;Chapter 2 of the Greenstone Developer's Guide. If the &amp;quot;Allow Extended &lt;br /&gt;Options&amp;quot; checkbox is ticked, some advanced formatting options are &lt;br /&gt;enabled. The list of features that can be formatted is changed slightly, and &lt;br /&gt;more variables are available to be used in the format command, providing &lt;br /&gt;greater control over the page layout.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Translate Text &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section describes the translation view, where you can define &lt;br /&gt;language-specific text fragments for parts of the collection's interface. &lt;br /&gt;Under &amp;quot;Design Sections&amp;quot;, click &amp;quot;Translate Text&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;First choose the an entry from the &amp;quot;Features&amp;quot; list. The language-specific &lt;br /&gt;strings associated with this feature appear below. Use the &amp;quot;Language of &lt;br /&gt;translation&amp;quot; pull-down list to select the target language, and type the &lt;br /&gt;translated text into the text area, referring to the &amp;quot;Initial Text Fragment&amp;quot; if &lt;br /&gt;necessary. Click &amp;quot;Add Translation&amp;quot; when finished.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To remove an existing translation, select it in the &amp;quot;Assigned Translations&amp;quot; &lt;br /&gt;table and click &amp;quot;Remove Translation&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To edit a translation, select it, edit it in the &amp;quot;Translated Text&amp;quot; text area, &lt;br /&gt;and click &amp;quot;Replace Translation&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Metadata Sets &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section explains the metadata set review panel. Under &amp;quot;Design &lt;br /&gt;Sections&amp;quot;, click &amp;quot;Metadata Sets&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This view is used to review the metadata sets that the collection uses, and &lt;br /&gt;the elements that are available within each set. Choose from the list of &lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;Available Metadata Sets&amp;quot; in order to see details of their elements.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To use another metadata set with the loaded collection, click &amp;quot;Add &lt;br /&gt;Metadata Set&amp;quot; and select the metadata set file (.mds) for the new metadata &lt;br /&gt;set.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Editing metadata sets is done with the Greenstone Editor for Metadata &lt;br /&gt;Sets (GEMS). Clicking the &amp;quot;Edit Metadata Set&amp;quot; button provides &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 49 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;information on how to run the GEMS.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you no longer need a metadata set, select it and press &amp;quot;Remove &lt;br /&gt;Metadata Set&amp;quot; to remove it. If you have assigned any metadata to &lt;br /&gt;elements in the removed set you will be asked how to deal with this &lt;br /&gt;metadata when you next open the collection.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Producing Your Collection &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having collected the documents for the collection, annotated them with &lt;br /&gt;metadata, and designed how the collection will appear, you can now &lt;br /&gt;produce the collection using Greenstone. This section explains how.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Create View &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Create view is used to create the collection by running Greenstone &lt;br /&gt;collection-building scripts on the information you have provided. &lt;br /&gt;Clicking &amp;quot;Build Collection&amp;quot; initiates the collection building process. The &lt;br /&gt;time this takes depends on the size of the collection and the number of &lt;br /&gt;indexes being created (for huge collections it can be hours). A progress &lt;br /&gt;bar indicates how much of the process has been completed. To cancel the &lt;br /&gt;process at any time, click &amp;quot;Cancel Build&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once the collection has successfully built, clicking &amp;quot;Preview Collection&amp;quot; &lt;br /&gt;will launch a web browser showing the home page of the collection. In &lt;br /&gt;Expert mode, you can use the &amp;quot;Message Log&amp;quot; entry at the left to review &lt;br /&gt;previous attempts to build the collection, whether successful or not. Select &lt;br /&gt;the log you want by clicking on the desired date in the &amp;quot;Log History&amp;quot; list.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Import and Build Settings &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section explains how to access the various import and build settings. &lt;br /&gt;For more information of importing and building read Chapter 1 of the &lt;br /&gt;Greenstone Developer's Guide -- Understanding the collection-building &lt;br /&gt;process.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Controlling the various settings is done in a similar way to the &lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;Configuring Arguments&amp;quot; window described in the Document Plugins &lt;br /&gt;section. Some fields require numeric arguments, and you can either type &lt;br /&gt;these in or use the up and down arrows to increase or decrease the current &lt;br /&gt;value (in some cases, the interface restricts the range you can enter). &lt;br /&gt;Others are enabled by clicking a checkbox (click again to disable).  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;50 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Miscellaneous &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section describes features of the Librarian Interface that are not &lt;br /&gt;associated with any particular view.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Preferences &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section explains the preferences dialog, accessed by opening &amp;quot;File&amp;quot; -&lt;br /&gt;&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Preferences&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first &amp;quot;General&amp;quot; option is a text field for entering your e-mail address. &lt;br /&gt;This will be used for the &amp;quot;creator&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;maintainer&amp;quot; collection metadata &lt;br /&gt;items. The next option is a pull-down list of the languages in which the &lt;br /&gt;Librarian Interface can be presented. If you change the dictionary by &lt;br /&gt;choosing one from the list, you must restart the Librarian Interface in &lt;br /&gt;order to load the new language strings from the dictionary.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If &amp;quot;View Extracted Metadata&amp;quot; is checked, the various controls dealing &lt;br /&gt;with metadata always show all metadata that has been extracted &lt;br /&gt;automatically from documents. Deselecting it hides this metadata &lt;br /&gt;(although it is still available during collection design, and within the final &lt;br /&gt;Greenstone collection). If &amp;quot;Show file sizes&amp;quot; is checked, the file size is &lt;br /&gt;shown next to each file in the Workspace and Collection file trees in the &lt;br /&gt;Gather and Enrich views.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;Mode&amp;quot; panel is used to control the level of detail within the &lt;br /&gt;interface. At its lowest setting, &amp;quot;Library Assistant&amp;quot;, the design view is &lt;br /&gt;disabled, arguments requiring regular expressions are hidden and the &lt;br /&gt;collection building produces a minimal log of events. In contrast the &lt;br /&gt;highest setting, &amp;quot;Expert&amp;quot;, provides access to all of the features of design, &lt;br /&gt;including plugin positioning and regular expression arguments, and also &lt;br /&gt;allows the full output from the collection building to be recorded in the &lt;br /&gt;logs. To change or review modes, click the radio button next to the mode &lt;br /&gt;you are interested in. You can quickly review what mode you are in by &lt;br /&gt;looking at the Librarian Interface's title bar.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Librarian Interface can support different workflows by determining &lt;br /&gt;which of the various view tabs are visible. Use the &amp;quot;Workflow&amp;quot; tab to &lt;br /&gt;customise what views are available by checking the boxes next to the &lt;br /&gt;views that you want to be available. Alternatively, use the pull-down list &lt;br /&gt;at the bottom to select predetermined configurations. Closing the &lt;br /&gt;preferences dialog establishes these workflow settings. These settings are &lt;br /&gt;stored with the collection, not in the Librarian Interface configuration file.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;Connection&amp;quot; tab lets you alter the path to the locally-running &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 51 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greenstone library server, which is used when Previewing collections. It &lt;br /&gt;also lets you set proxy information for connecting to the Internet (e.g. &lt;br /&gt;when downloading files; see the Downloading Files From the Internet &lt;br /&gt;section for details). Check the box to enable proxy connection and supply &lt;br /&gt;details of the proxy host address and port number. The proxy connection &lt;br /&gt;is established when you close the Preferences dialog.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the course of a session the Librarian Interface may give warning &lt;br /&gt;messages which inform you of possibly unforeseen consequences of an &lt;br /&gt;action. You can disable the messages by checking the &amp;quot;Do not show this &lt;br /&gt;warning again&amp;quot; box. You can re-enable warning messages using the &lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;Warnings&amp;quot; tab. Check the box next to warning messages you want to see &lt;br /&gt;again.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;File Associations &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Librarian Interface uses particular application programs to open &lt;br /&gt;particular file types. This section explains how to assign and edit these &lt;br /&gt;file associations.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To alter file associations open the &amp;quot;File&amp;quot; menu and click &amp;quot;File &lt;br /&gt;Associations...&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To add an association, select the target file extension from the pull-down &lt;br /&gt;list, or type in a new extension (do not include the &amp;quot;.&amp;quot;). Next either type &lt;br /&gt;command that launches the desired application in the appropriate field, or &lt;br /&gt;choose the application from the &amp;quot;Browse&amp;quot; dialog. &amp;quot;%1&amp;quot; can be used in the &lt;br /&gt;launch command to insert the name of the file being opened. Once these &lt;br /&gt;are filled out, &amp;quot;Add Association&amp;quot; is enabled and can be clicked to add the &lt;br /&gt;association.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To edit an association, select an existing file extension. Any existing &lt;br /&gt;associated command is shown in the launch command field. Edit it, and &lt;br /&gt;then click &amp;quot;Replace Association&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To remove an association, select an existing file extension and click &lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;Remove Association&amp;quot;. (The file extension remains in the &amp;quot;For Files &lt;br /&gt;Ending&amp;quot; pull-down list.)  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;File associations are stored in the Librarian Interface's main folder, in a &lt;br /&gt;file called &amp;quot;associations.xml&amp;quot;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exporting Collections to CD-ROM &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section describes how to export collections to a self-installing &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;52 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greenstone CD-ROM.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greenstone can export one or more collections to a self-installing CD-&lt;br /&gt;ROM for Windows. To do so, Greenstone's &amp;quot;Export to CD-ROM&amp;quot; &lt;br /&gt;package must be installed. This is not included by default, so you may &lt;br /&gt;need to modify your installation to include it.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To export a collection, open the &amp;quot;File&amp;quot; menu and choose &amp;quot;Export to CD-&lt;br /&gt;ROM&amp;quot;. A list of Greenstone collections appears; click on any one to see &lt;br /&gt;its description. Tick the check boxes of the collections to export. You can &lt;br /&gt;enter the CD-ROM's name in the box: this is what will appear in the Start &lt;br /&gt;menu when the CD-ROM has been installed. Then click &amp;quot;Export&amp;quot;. The &lt;br /&gt;process involves copying many files and may take a few minutes.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Upon completion, Greenstone will show the name of a folder containing &lt;br /&gt;the exported collections. Use a CD writer to copy its contents to a blank &lt;br /&gt;CD-ROM.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;3.3 Tagging document files &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Source documents often need to be structured into sections and &lt;br /&gt;subsections, and this information needs to be communicated to &lt;br /&gt;Greenstone so that it can preserve the hierarchical structure. Also, &lt;br /&gt;metadata - typically the title - might be associated with each section and &lt;br /&gt;subsection. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The source documents from an OCR process are typically a set of word &lt;br /&gt;processor files, including images. If these are represented as Microsoft &lt;br /&gt;Word files, they can be input into Greenstone using the Word plugin. &lt;br /&gt;Alternatively, they can be converted to HTML and input using the HTML &lt;br /&gt;plugin. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In either case, the hierarchical structure of a document may be indicated &lt;br /&gt;by inserting tags in the text as follows: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;!--  &lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;Section&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;  &amp;lt;Description&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;    &amp;lt;Metadata name=&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Realizing human rights for poor  &lt;br /&gt;       people: Strategies for achieving the international  &lt;br /&gt;       development targets&amp;lt;/Metadata&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;  &amp;lt;/Description&amp;gt;  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 53 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;--&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;(text of section goes here)  &lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;!--  &lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;/Section&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;--&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;lt;!-- ... --&amp;gt; markers are used because they indicate comments in &lt;br /&gt;HTML; thus these section tags will not affect document formatting. You &lt;br /&gt;must include these markers around your section tags, even if the &lt;br /&gt;document you are working with is not HTML (e.g. if it's a Microsoft &lt;br /&gt;Word file). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the Description part (between the &amp;lt;Description&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;/Description&amp;gt; &lt;br /&gt;tags) other kinds of metadata can be specified, but this is not done for the &lt;br /&gt;style of collections we are describing here. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is important to remember that you are creating a hierarchical table of &lt;br /&gt;contents when you insert section tags into your document. This means &lt;br /&gt;that sections can be nested within other sections. In fact, all sections must &lt;br /&gt;be nested within a single enclosing section that encompasses the entire &lt;br /&gt;document. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following example demonstrates a document with two chapters, the &lt;br /&gt;second of which contains two subsections. For real examples of source &lt;br /&gt;documents tagged in this way, look at the source documents for the Demo &lt;br /&gt;or DLS collections. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;!--  &lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;Section&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;  &amp;lt;Description&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;    &amp;lt;Metadata name=&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot;&amp;gt;My Document&amp;lt;/Metadata&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;  &amp;lt;/Description&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;  &amp;lt;Section&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;    &amp;lt;Description&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;      &amp;lt;Metadata name=&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Chapter 1&amp;lt;/Metadata&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;    &amp;lt;/Description&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;--&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;(text of chapter 1 goes here)  &lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;!--  &lt;br /&gt;  &amp;lt;/Section&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;  &amp;lt;Section&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;    &amp;lt;Description&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;      &amp;lt;Metadata name=&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Chapter 2&amp;lt;/Metadata&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;    &amp;lt;/Description&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;    &amp;lt;Section&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;      &amp;lt;Description&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;        &amp;lt;Metadata name=&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Subsection 1&amp;lt;/Metadata&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;      &amp;lt;/Description&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;--&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;(text of sub-section 1 goes here)  &lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;!--  &lt;br /&gt;    &amp;lt;/Section&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;    &amp;lt;Section&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;      &amp;lt;Description&amp;gt;  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;54 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;        &amp;lt;Metadata name=&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Subsection 2&amp;lt;/Metadata&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;      &amp;lt;/Description&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;--&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;(text of sub-section 2 goes here)  &lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;!--  &lt;br /&gt;    &amp;lt;/Section&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;  &amp;lt;/Section&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;/Section&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;--&amp;gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that metadata assigned from within a section tag in a source &lt;br /&gt;document takes precedence over that assigned to the document as a &lt;br /&gt;whole. This means that you should not explicitly specify Title metadata &lt;br /&gt;for the top-level section within a source document unless you want it to &lt;br /&gt;override the title you gave it when specifying metadata. In the above &lt;br /&gt;example, unless you want to override the document’s existing title you &lt;br /&gt;should omit the line that reads: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &amp;lt;Metadata name=&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot;&amp;gt;My Document&amp;lt;/Metadata&amp;gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 55 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;3.4 The Collector &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Collector is a facility that helps you create new collections, modify or &lt;br /&gt;add to existing ones, or delete collections. To do this you will be guided &lt;br /&gt;through a sequence of web pages which request the information that is &lt;br /&gt;needed. The sequence is self-explanatory: this section takes you through &lt;br /&gt;it. As an alternative to using the Collector, you can also build collections &lt;br /&gt;from the command line—the first few pages of the Developer’s Guide &lt;br /&gt;give a detailed walk-through of how to do this. The Collector predates the &lt;br /&gt;librarian interface described in Section 3.1, and for most practical &lt;br /&gt;purposes the librarian interface should be used instead of the Collector. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building and distributing information collections carries responsibilities &lt;br /&gt;that you should reflect on before you begin. There are legal issues of &lt;br /&gt;copyright: being able to access documents doesn’t mean you can &lt;br /&gt;necessarily give them to others. There are social issues: collections should &lt;br /&gt;respect the customs of the community out of which the documents arise. &lt;br /&gt;And there are ethical issues: some things simply should not be made &lt;br /&gt;available to others. The pen is mightier than the sword!—be sensitive to &lt;br /&gt;the power of information and use it wisely.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To access the Collector, click the appropriate link on the digital library &lt;br /&gt;home page.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Greenstone, the structure of a particular collection is determined when &lt;br /&gt;the collection is set up. This includes such things as the format of the &lt;br /&gt;source documents, how they should be displayed on the screen, the source &lt;br /&gt;of metadata, what browsing facilities should be provided, what full-text &lt;br /&gt;search indexes should be provided, and how the search results should be &lt;br /&gt;displayed. Once the collection is in place, it is easy to add new documents &lt;br /&gt;to it—so long as they have the same format as the existing documents, &lt;br /&gt;and the same type of metadata is provided, in exactly the same way. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Collector has the following basic functions: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. create a new collection with the same structure as an existing one; &lt;br /&gt;2. create a new collection with a different structure from existing ones; &lt;br /&gt;3. add new material to an existing collection; &lt;br /&gt;4. modify the structure of an existing collection; &lt;br /&gt;5. delete a collection; and &lt;br /&gt;6. write an existing collection to a self-contained, self-installing CD-&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;ROM. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 16 shows the Collector being used to create a new collection, in &lt;br /&gt;this case from a set of HTML files stored locally. You must first decide &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;56 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;whether to work with an existing collection or build a new one. The &lt;br /&gt;former case covers options 1 and 2 above; the latter covers options 3–6. &lt;br /&gt;In Figure 16a, the user opts to create a new collection. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Logging in &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Either way it is necessary to log in before proceeding. Note that in &lt;br /&gt;general, people use their web browser to access the collection-building &lt;br /&gt;facility on a remote computer, and build the collection on that server. Of &lt;br /&gt;course, we cannot allow arbitrary people to build collections (for reasons &lt;br /&gt;of propriety if nothing else), so Greenstone contains a security system &lt;br /&gt;which forces people who want to build collections to log in first. This &lt;br /&gt;allows a central system to offer a service to those wishing to build &lt;br /&gt;information collections and use that server to make them available to &lt;br /&gt;others. Alternatively, if you are running Greenstone on your own &lt;br /&gt;computer you can build collections locally, but it is still necessary to log &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 16  Using the &lt;br /&gt;Collector to build a &lt;br /&gt;new collection &lt;br /&gt;(continued on next &lt;br /&gt;pages) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;(a) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 57 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;in because other people who use the Greenstone system on your computer &lt;br /&gt;should not be allowed to build collections without prior permission. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dialog structure &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Upon completion of login, the page in Figure 16b appears. This shows the &lt;br /&gt;sequence of steps that are involved in collection building. They are: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. Collection information &lt;br /&gt;2. Source data &lt;br /&gt;3. Configuring the collection &lt;br /&gt;4. Building the collection &lt;br /&gt;5. Viewing the collection. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first step is to specify the collection’s name and associated &lt;br /&gt;information. The second is to say where the source data is to come from. &lt;br /&gt;The third is to adjust the configuration options, a step that becomes more &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 16  (Continued) (b) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;58 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;useful as you gain experience with Greenstone. The fourth step is where &lt;br /&gt;all the (computer’s) work is done. During the “building” process the &lt;br /&gt;system makes all the indexes and gathers together any other information &lt;br /&gt;that is required to make the collection operate. The fifth step is to view &lt;br /&gt;the collection that has been created. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;These five steps are displayed as a linear sequence of gray buttons at the &lt;br /&gt;bottom of the screen in Figure 16b, and at the bottom of all other pages &lt;br /&gt;generated by the Collector. This display helps users keep track of where &lt;br /&gt;they are in the process. The button that should be clicked to continue the &lt;br /&gt;sequence is shown in green (collection information in Figure 16b). The &lt;br /&gt;gray buttons (all the others, in Figure 16b) are inactive. The buttons &lt;br /&gt;change to yellow as you proceed through the sequence, and the user can &lt;br /&gt;return to an earlier step by clicking the corresponding yellow button in the &lt;br /&gt;diagram. This display is modeled after the “wizards” that are widely used &lt;br /&gt;in commercial software to guide users through the steps involved in &lt;br /&gt;installing new software. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collection information &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next step in the sequence, collection information, is shown in Figure &lt;br /&gt;16c. When creating a new collection, it is necessary to enter some &lt;br /&gt;information about it: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• title, &lt;br /&gt;• contact E-mail address, and &lt;br /&gt;• brief description. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The collection title is a short phrase used through the digital library to &lt;br /&gt;identify the content of the collection. Example titles include Food and &lt;br /&gt;Nutrition Library, World Environmental Library, Development Library, &lt;br /&gt;and so on. The E-mail address specifies the first point of contact for any &lt;br /&gt;problems encountered with the collection. If the Greenstone software &lt;br /&gt;detects a problem, a diagnostic report may be sent to this address. Finally, &lt;br /&gt;the brief description is a statement describing the principles that govern &lt;br /&gt;what is included in the collection. It appears under the heading About this &lt;br /&gt;collection on the first page when the collection is presented. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The user’s current position in the collection-building sequence is &lt;br /&gt;indicated by an arrow that appears in the display at the bottom of each &lt;br /&gt;screen—in this case, as Figure 16c shows, the collection information &lt;br /&gt;stage. The user proceeds to Figure 16d by clicking the green source data &lt;br /&gt;button. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 59 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Source data &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 16d is the point where the user specifies the source text that &lt;br /&gt;comprises the collection. You may either base your collection on a default &lt;br /&gt;structure that is provided, or on the structure of an existing collection. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you opt for the default structure, the new collection may contain HTML &lt;br /&gt;documents (files ending in .htm, .html), or plain text documents (files &lt;br /&gt;ending in .txt, .text), Microsoft Word documents (files ending in .doc), &lt;br /&gt;PDF documents (files ending in .pdf) or E-mail documents (files ending &lt;br /&gt;in .email). More information about the different document formats that &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 16  (Continued) (c) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;60 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;can be accommodated is given in the section on “Document formats” &lt;br /&gt;below. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you base your new collection on an existing one, the files in the new &lt;br /&gt;collection must be exactly the same type as those used to build the &lt;br /&gt;existing one. Note that some collections use non-standard input file &lt;br /&gt;formats, while others use metadata specified in auxiliary files. If your new &lt;br /&gt;input lacks this information, some browsing facilities may not work &lt;br /&gt;properly. For example, if you clone the Demo collection you may find &lt;br /&gt;that the subjects, organization, and how to buttons don’t work. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 16  (Continued) (d) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 61 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Boxes are provided to indicate where the source documents are located: &lt;br /&gt;up to three separate input sources can be specified in Figure 16d. If you &lt;br /&gt;need more, just click the button marked “more sources.” &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are three kinds of specification: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• a directory name on the Greenstone server system (beginning with &lt;br /&gt;“file://”) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• an address beginning with “http://” for files to be downloaded from &lt;br /&gt;the web &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• an address beginning with “ftp://” for files to be downloaded using &lt;br /&gt;anonymous FTP. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you use file:// or ftp:// to specify a file, that file will be downloaded. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you use http:// it depends on whether the URL gives you a normal web &lt;br /&gt;page in your browser, or a list of files. If a page, that page will be &lt;br /&gt;downloaded—and so will all pages it links to, and all pages they link to, &lt;br /&gt;etc.—provided they reside on the same site, below the URL. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you use file:// or ftp:// to specify a folder or directory, or give a http:// &lt;br /&gt;URL that leads to a list of files, everything in the folder and all its &lt;br /&gt;subfolders will be included in the collection. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can specify sources of more than one type.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this case (Figure 16d) the new collection will contain documents taken &lt;br /&gt;from a local file system as well as a remote web site, which will be &lt;br /&gt;mirrored during the building process.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you click the configure collection button to proceed to the next &lt;br /&gt;stage of building, the Collector checks that all the sources of input you &lt;br /&gt;specified can be reached. This might take a few seconds, or even a few &lt;br /&gt;minutes if you have specified several sources. If one or more of the input &lt;br /&gt;sources you specified is unavailable, you will be presented with a page &lt;br /&gt;like that in Figure 16e, where the unavailable sources are marked (both of &lt;br /&gt;them in this case). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sources might be unavailable because  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• the file, FTP site or URL does not exist;  &lt;br /&gt;• you need to dial up your ISP first;  &lt;br /&gt;• you are trying to access a URL from behind a firewall.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;62 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last case is potentially the most mysterious. It occurs if you normally &lt;br /&gt;have to present a username and password to access the Internet &lt;br /&gt;Sometimes it happens that you can see the page from your Web browser &lt;br /&gt;if you enter the URL, but the Collector claims that it is unavailable. The &lt;br /&gt;explanation is that the page in your browser may be coming from a &lt;br /&gt;locally cached copy. Unfortunately, locally cached copies are invisible to &lt;br /&gt;the Collector. In this case we recommend that you download the pages &lt;br /&gt;using your browser first. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 16  (Continued) (e) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 63 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Configuring the collection &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 16f shows the next stage. The construction and presentation of all &lt;br /&gt;collections is controlled by specifications in a special collection &lt;br /&gt;configuration file (see below). Advanced users may use this page to alter &lt;br /&gt;the configuration settings. Most, however, will proceed directly to the &lt;br /&gt;final stage. Indeed, in Figure 16d both the configure collection and the &lt;br /&gt;build collection buttons are displayed in green, signifying that step 3 can &lt;br /&gt;be bypassed completely. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In our example the user has made a small modification to the default &lt;br /&gt;configuration file by including the file_is_url flag with the HTML plugin. &lt;br /&gt;This flag causes URL metadata to be inserted in each document, based on &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 16  (Continued) (f) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;64 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;the filename convention that is adopted by the mirroring package. This &lt;br /&gt;metadata is used in the collection to allow readers to refer to the original &lt;br /&gt;source material, rather than to a local copy. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building the collection &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 16g shows the “building” stage. Up until now, the responses to the &lt;br /&gt;dialog have merely been recorded in a temporary file. The building stage &lt;br /&gt;is where the action takes place. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;During building, indexes for both browsing and searching are constructed &lt;br /&gt;according to instructions in the collection configuration file. The building &lt;br /&gt;process takes some time: minutes to hours, depending on the size of the &lt;br /&gt;collection and the speed of your computer. Some very large collections &lt;br /&gt;take a day or more to build. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you reach this stage in the interaction, a status line at the bottom of &lt;br /&gt;the web page gives feedback on how the operation is progressing, updated &lt;br /&gt;every five seconds. The message visible in Figure 16f indicates that when &lt;br /&gt;the snapshot was taken, Title metadata was being extracted from an input &lt;br /&gt;file. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Warnings are written if input files or URLs are requested that do not &lt;br /&gt;exist, or exist but there is no plugin that can process them, or the plugin &lt;br /&gt;cannot find an associated file, such as an image file embedded in a HTML &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 16  (Continued) (g) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 65 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;document. The intention is that you will monitor progress by keeping this &lt;br /&gt;window open in your browser. If any errors cause the process to &lt;br /&gt;terminate, they are recorded in this status area. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can stop the building process at any time by clicking on the stop &lt;br /&gt;building button in Figure 16g. If you leave the web page (and have not &lt;br /&gt;cancelled the building process with the stop building button), the building &lt;br /&gt;operation will continue, and the new collection will be installed when the &lt;br /&gt;operation completes. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Viewing the collection &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When the collection is built and installed, the sequence of buttons visible &lt;br /&gt;at the bottom of Figures 16b–f appears at the bottom of Figure 16g, with &lt;br /&gt;the View collection button active. This takes the user directly to the newly &lt;br /&gt;built collection. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, there is a facility for E-mail to be sent to the collection’s contact &lt;br /&gt;E-mail address, and to the system’s administrator, whenever a collection &lt;br /&gt;is created (or modified.) This allows those responsible to check when &lt;br /&gt;changes occur, and monitor what is happening on the system. The facility &lt;br /&gt;is disabled by default but can be enabled by editing the main.cfg &lt;br /&gt;configuration file (see the Greenstone Digital Library Developer’s Guide, &lt;br /&gt;Section 4). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Working with existing collections &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you enter the Collector you have to specify whether you want to &lt;br /&gt;create an entirely new collection or work with an existing one, adding &lt;br /&gt;data to it or deleting it. By creating all searching and browsing structures &lt;br /&gt;automatically from the documents themselves Greenstone makes it easy &lt;br /&gt;to add new information to existing collections. Because no links are &lt;br /&gt;inserted by hand, when new documents in the same format become &lt;br /&gt;available they can be merged into the collection automatically.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To work with an existing collection, you first select the collection from a &lt;br /&gt;list that is provided. Some collections are “write protected” and cannot be &lt;br /&gt;altered: these ones don’t appear in the selection list. With the collection, &lt;br /&gt;you can  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Add more data and rebuild the collection &lt;br /&gt;• Edit the collection configuration file &lt;br /&gt;• Delete the collection entirely &lt;br /&gt;• Export the collection to CD-ROM. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;66 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add new data &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The files that you specify will be added to the collection. Make sure that &lt;br /&gt;you do not re-specify files that are already in the collection—otherwise &lt;br /&gt;two copies will be included. Files are identified by their full pathname, &lt;br /&gt;web pages by their absolute web address. You specify directories and &lt;br /&gt;files just as you do when building a new collection. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you add data to a collection and for some reason the building process &lt;br /&gt;fails, the old version of the collection remains unchanged. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit configuration file &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advanced users can edit the collection configuration file, just as they can &lt;br /&gt;when a new collection is built.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Delete the collection &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;You will be asked to confirm whether you really want to delete the &lt;br /&gt;collection. Once deleted, Greenstone can not bring the collection back! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Export the collection &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can export the collection in a form that allows it to be written to a &lt;br /&gt;self-contained, self-installing Greenstone CD-ROM for Windows. &lt;br /&gt;Because commercial software that creates self-installing CD-ROMs is &lt;br /&gt;expensive, this facility includes a homegrown installer module. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you export the collection, the dialogue informs you of the directory &lt;br /&gt;name in which the result has been placed. The entire contents of the &lt;br /&gt;directory should be written on to CD-ROM using a standard CD-writing &lt;br /&gt;utility. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The immense variety of different possible Windows configurations has &lt;br /&gt;made it difficult for us to test and debug the Greenstone installer under all &lt;br /&gt;possible conditions. Although the installer produces CD-ROMs that &lt;br /&gt;operate on most Windows systems, it is still under development. If you &lt;br /&gt;experience problems and you possess a commercial installation package &lt;br /&gt;(e.g. InstallShield), you can use it to create CD-ROMs from the &lt;br /&gt;information that Greenstone provides. The above-mentioned export &lt;br /&gt;directory contains four files that relate to the installation process, and &lt;br /&gt;three subdirectories that contain the complete collection and software. &lt;br /&gt;Remove the four files and use InstallShield to make a CD-ROM image &lt;br /&gt;that installs these directories and creates a shortcut to the program &lt;br /&gt;gsdl\\server.exe. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS 67 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Document formats &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When building collections, Greenstone processes each different format of &lt;br /&gt;source document by seeking a “plugin” that can deal with that particular &lt;br /&gt;format. Plugins are specified in the collection configuration file. &lt;br /&gt;Greenstone generally uses the filename to determine document formats—&lt;br /&gt;for example, foo.txt is processed as a text file, foo.html as HTML, and &lt;br /&gt;foo.doc as a Word file. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is a summary of the plugins that are available for widely-used &lt;br /&gt;document formats. More detail about these plugins, and additional plugins &lt;br /&gt;for less commonly-used formats, can be found in the Greenstone Digital &lt;br /&gt;Library Developer’s Guide. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;TEXTPlug (*.txt, *.text) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;TEXTPlug interprets a plain text file as a simple document. It adds title &lt;br /&gt;metadata based on the first line of the file. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;HTMLPlug (*.htm, *.html; also .shtml, .shm, .asp, .php, .cgi) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;HTMLPlug processes HTML files. It extracts title metadata based on the &lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;title&amp;gt; tag; other metadata expressed using HTML’s metatag syntax can be &lt;br /&gt;extracted too. There are many options available with this plugin, &lt;br /&gt;documented in the Greenstone Digital Library Developer’s Guide. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;WORDPlug (*.doc) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;WORDPlug imports Microsoft Word documents. There are many &lt;br /&gt;different variants on the Word format—and even Microsoft programs &lt;br /&gt;frequently make conversion errors. Greenstone uses independent &lt;br /&gt;programs to convert Word files to HTML. For some older Word formats &lt;br /&gt;the system resorts to a simple extraction algorithm that finds all text &lt;br /&gt;strings in the input file.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;PDFPlug (*.pdf) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;PDFPlug imports documents in PDF Adobe’s Portable Document Format. &lt;br /&gt;Like WORDPlug, it uses an independent program, in this case pdftohtml, &lt;br /&gt;to convert PDF files to HTML.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;As with WORDPlug, by default collections will display the HTML &lt;br /&gt;equivalent of the file when the user clicks the document icon; however, &lt;br /&gt;the format strings in the collection configuration file can be adjusted to &lt;br /&gt;give the user access to the original PDF file instead, and we recommend &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;68 MAKING GREENSTONE COLLECTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;that you do this. Again, just replace the &amp;lt;link&amp;gt; … &amp;lt;/link&amp;gt; tags by &lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;srclink&amp;gt; … &amp;lt;/srclink&amp;gt; ones. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pdftohtml program fails on some PDF files. What happens is that the &lt;br /&gt;conversion process takes an exceptionally long time, and often an error &lt;br /&gt;message relating to the conversion process appears on the screen. If this &lt;br /&gt;occurs, the only solution that we can offer is to remove the offending &lt;br /&gt;document from the collection. Also, PDFPlug cannot handle encrypted &lt;br /&gt;PDF files. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;PSPlug (*.ps) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;PSPlug imports documents in PostScript. It works best if a standard Linux &lt;br /&gt;program, called ps2ascii, is already installed on your computer. This is &lt;br /&gt;available on most Linux installations, but not on Windows. If this &lt;br /&gt;program is not available, PSPlug resorts to a simple text extraction &lt;br /&gt;algorithm. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;EMAILPlug (*.email) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;EMAILPlug imports files containing E-mail, and deals with common E-&lt;br /&gt;mail formats such as are used by the Netscape, Eudora, and Unix mail &lt;br /&gt;readers. Each source document is examined to see if it contains an E-mail, &lt;br /&gt;or several E-mails joined together in one file, and if so its contents are &lt;br /&gt;processed. The plugin extracts Subject, To, From, and Date metadata. &lt;br /&gt;However, this plugin does not yet handle MIME-encoded E-mails &lt;br /&gt;properly—although legible, they often look rather strange. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;ZIPPlug (.gz, .z, .tgz, .taz, .bz, .zip, .tar) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;ZIPPlug plugin handles the following compressed and/or archived input &lt;br /&gt;formats: gzip (.gz, .z, .tgz, .taz), bzip (.bz), zip (.zip .jar), and tar (.tar). It &lt;br /&gt;relies on the programs gunzip, bunzip, unzip, and tar, which are standard &lt;br /&gt;Linux utilities. ZIPPlug is disabled on Windows computers.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;greenstone.org  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;4 &lt;br /&gt;Administration &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;An “administrative” facility is included with every Greenstone &lt;br /&gt;installation. To access this facility, click the appropriate link on the front &lt;br /&gt;page. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The entry page, shown in Figure 17, gives information about each of the &lt;br /&gt;collections offered by the system. Note that all collections are included—&lt;br /&gt;for there may be “private” ones that do not appear on the Greenstone &lt;br /&gt;home page. With each is given its short name, full name, whether it is &lt;br /&gt;publicly displayed, and whether or not it is running. Clicking a particular &lt;br /&gt;collection’s abbreviation (the first column of links in Figure 17) brings up &lt;br /&gt;information about that collection, gathered from its collection &lt;br /&gt;configuration file and from other internal structures created for that &lt;br /&gt;collection. If the collection is both public and running, clicking the &lt;br /&gt;collection’s full name (the second link) takes you to the collection itself. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A collection named wohiex, for Women’s History Excerpt, is visible near &lt;br /&gt;the bottom of Figure 17. Figure 18 shows the information that is &lt;br /&gt;displayed when this link is clicked. The first section gives some &lt;br /&gt;information from the configuration file, and the size of the collection &lt;br /&gt;(about 1000 documents, about a million words, over 6 Mb). The next &lt;br /&gt;sections contain internal information related to the communication &lt;br /&gt;protocol through which collections are accessed. For example, the filter &lt;br /&gt;options for “QueryFilter” show the options and possible values that can &lt;br /&gt;be used when querying the collection. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The administrative facility also presents configuration information about &lt;br /&gt;the installation and allows it to be modified. It facilitates examination of &lt;br /&gt;the error logs that record internal errors, and the user logs that record &lt;br /&gt;usage. It enables a specified user (or users) to authorize others to build &lt;br /&gt;collections and add new material to existing ones. All these facilities are &lt;br /&gt;accessed interactively from the menu items at the left-hand side of &lt;br /&gt;Figure 17.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;70 ADMINISTRATION &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 17 Greenstone &lt;br /&gt;Administration facility &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;ADMINISTRATION 71 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 18 Information &lt;br /&gt;about the Women’s &lt;br /&gt;History Excerpt &lt;br /&gt;collection &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;72 ADMINISTRATION &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;4.1 Configuration files  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are two configuration files that control Greenstone’s operation, the &lt;br /&gt;site configuration file gsdlsite.cfg and the main configuration file &lt;br /&gt;main.cfg. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The gsdlsite.cfg file is used to configure the Greenstone software for the &lt;br /&gt;site where it is installed. It is designed for keeping configuration options &lt;br /&gt;that are particular to a given site. Examples include the name of the &lt;br /&gt;directory where the Greenstone software is kept, the HTTP address of the &lt;br /&gt;Greenstone system, and whether the fastcgi facility is being used. The &lt;br /&gt;entries in this file are described in the Greenstone Digital Library &lt;br /&gt;Installation Guide. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main.cfg file contains information that is common to the interface of &lt;br /&gt;all collections served by a Greenstone site. It includes the E-mail address &lt;br /&gt;of the system maintainer, whether the status and collector pages are &lt;br /&gt;enabled, whether logs of user activity are kept, and whether Internet &lt;br /&gt;“cookies” are used to identify users. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;4.2 Logs &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Three kinds of logs can be examined: usage logs, error logs and &lt;br /&gt;initialization logs. The last two are only really of interest to people &lt;br /&gt;maintaining the software. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;All user activity—every page that each user visits—can be recorded by &lt;br /&gt;the Greenstone software, though no personal names are included in the &lt;br /&gt;logs. Logging, disabled by default, is enabled by including the lines &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;logcgiargs true  &lt;br /&gt;usecookies true &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;in the main system configuration file. Both options are false by default, so &lt;br /&gt;that no logging is done unless they are set. It is the logcgiargs line that &lt;br /&gt;actually turns logging on and off. By activating usecookies a unique &lt;br /&gt;identification code is assigned to each user, which enables individual &lt;br /&gt;user’s interactions to be traced through the log file. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each line in the user log records a page visited—even the pages generated &lt;br /&gt;to inspect the log files! It contains (a) the IP address of the user’s &lt;br /&gt;computer, (b) a timestamp in square brackets, (c) the CGI arguments in &lt;br /&gt;parentheses, and (d) the name of the user’s browser (Netscape is called &lt;br /&gt;“Mozilla”). Here is a sample line, split and annotated for ease of reading: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;ADMINISTRATION 73 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;/fast-cgi-bin/niupepalibrary &lt;br /&gt;(a) its-www1.massey.ac.nz  &lt;br /&gt;(b) [Thu Dec 07 23:47:00 NZDT 2000] &lt;br /&gt;(c) (a=p, b=0, bcp=, beu=, c=niupepa, cc=, ccp=0, ccs=0, cl=, cm=, &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;cq2=, d=, e=, er=, f=0, fc=1, gc=0, gg=text, gt=0, h=, h2=, hl=1, &lt;br /&gt;hp=, il=l, j=, j2=, k=1, ky=, l=en, m=50, n=, n2=, o=20, p=home, &lt;br /&gt;pw=, q=, q2=, r=1, s=0, sp=frameset, t=1, ua=, uan=, ug=, &lt;br /&gt;uma=listusers, umc=, umnpw1=, umnpw2=, umpw=, umug=, umun=, umus=, &lt;br /&gt;un=, us=invalid, v=0, w=w, x=0, z=130.123.128.4-950647871)  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;(d) “Mozilla/4.08 [en] (Win95; I ;Nav)” &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last CGI argument, “z”, is an identification code or “cookie” &lt;br /&gt;generated by the user’s browser: it comprises the user’s IP number &lt;br /&gt;followed by the timestamp when they first accessed the digital library. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The log file usage.txt is placed in the etc directory in the Greenstone file &lt;br /&gt;structure (see the Greenstone Digital Library Developer’s Guide). When &lt;br /&gt;logging is enabled, every action by every user is logged. However, only &lt;br /&gt;the last 100 entries in the log file are displayed by the usage log link in &lt;br /&gt;Figure 17. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;4.3 User management &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greenstone incorporates an authentication scheme which can be used to &lt;br /&gt;control access to certain facilities. At the moment this is only used to &lt;br /&gt;restrict the people who are allowed to enter the Collector and certain &lt;br /&gt;administration functions. If, for a particular collection, it were necessary &lt;br /&gt;to authenticate users before returning information to them, this is possible &lt;br /&gt;too—for example, documents could be protected on an individual basis so &lt;br /&gt;that they can only be accessed by registered users on presentation of a &lt;br /&gt;password. However, no current collections use this facility). &lt;br /&gt;Authentication is done by requesting a user name and password, as &lt;br /&gt;illustrated in Figure 16a. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the administration page users can be listed, new ones added, and old &lt;br /&gt;ones deleted. The ability to do this is of course also protected: only users &lt;br /&gt;who have administrative privileges can add new users. It is also possible &lt;br /&gt;for each user to belong to different “groups”. At present, the only extant &lt;br /&gt;groups are “administrator” and “colbuilder”. Members of the first group &lt;br /&gt;can add and remove users, and change their groups. Members of the &lt;br /&gt;second can access the facilities described above to build new collections &lt;br /&gt;and alter (and delete) existing ones. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When Greenstone is installed, there is one user called admin who belongs &lt;br /&gt;to both groups. The password for this user is set during the installation &lt;br /&gt;process. This user can create new names and passwords for users who &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;74 ADMINISTRATION &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;belong just to the colbuilder group, which is the recommended way of &lt;br /&gt;giving other users the ability to build collections. User information is &lt;br /&gt;recorded in two databases that are placed in the Greenstone file structure &lt;br /&gt;(see the Greenstone Digital Library Developer’s Guide). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;4.4 Technical information &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The links under the Technical information heading show further &lt;br /&gt;information on the installation. The general link gives access to technical &lt;br /&gt;information, including the directories where things are stored. The &lt;br /&gt;protocols menu item gives, for each possible protocol type, information &lt;br /&gt;about each of the collections supported by that protocol. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, user interface code (called the “receptionist”) uses actions to &lt;br /&gt;communicate the wishes of the user. These actions correspond to the CGI &lt;br /&gt;argument labeled a. For example, if a=status the receptionist invokes the &lt;br /&gt;status action (which displays the status page). A menu item gives access &lt;br /&gt;to lists of all actions supported by the system, and another leads to the &lt;br /&gt;arguments that these actions take. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;greenstone.org  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Appendix A &lt;br /&gt;Software features &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Accessible via web &lt;br /&gt;browser &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collections are accessed through a standard web browser (Netscape or &lt;br /&gt;Internet Explorer) and combine easy-to-use browsing with powerful &lt;br /&gt;search facilities. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Full-text and fielded &lt;br /&gt;search &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The user can search the full text of the documents, or choose between&lt;br /&gt;indexes built from different parts of the documents. For example, some &lt;br /&gt;collections have an index of full documents, an index of sections, an&lt;br /&gt;index of titles, and an index of authors, each of which can be searched for&lt;br /&gt;particular words or phrases. Results can be ranked by relevance or sorted &lt;br /&gt;by a metadata element. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Flexible browsing &lt;br /&gt;facilities &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The user can browse lists of authors, lists of titles, lists of dates,&lt;br /&gt;classification structures, and so on. Different collections may offer&lt;br /&gt;different browsing facilities and even within a collection, a broad variety &lt;br /&gt;of browsing interfaces are available. Browsing and searching interfaces&lt;br /&gt;are constructed during the building process, according to collection&lt;br /&gt;configuration information. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Creates access &lt;br /&gt;structures &lt;br /&gt;automatically &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Greenstone software creates information collections that are very &lt;br /&gt;easy to maintain. All searching and browsing structures are built directly&lt;br /&gt;from the documents themselves. No links are inserted by hand, but&lt;br /&gt;existing links in originals are maintained. This means that if new &lt;br /&gt;documents in the same format become available, they can be merged into&lt;br /&gt;the collection automatically. Indeed, for some collections this is done by&lt;br /&gt;processes that wake up regularly, scout for new material, and rebuild the&lt;br /&gt;indexes—all without manual intervention. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;76 APPENDIX A—SOFTWARE FEATURES &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Makes use of available &lt;br /&gt;metadata &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Metadata, which is descriptive information such as author, title, date,&lt;br /&gt;keywords, and so on, may be associated with each document, or with&lt;br /&gt;individual sections within documents. Metadata is used as the raw&lt;br /&gt;material for browsing indexes. It must be either provided explicitly or&lt;br /&gt;derivable automatically from the source documents. The Dublin Core&lt;br /&gt;metadata scheme is used for most electronic documents, however,&lt;br /&gt;provision is made for other schemes. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plugins extend the &lt;br /&gt;system’s capabilities &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to accommodate different kinds of source documents, the&lt;br /&gt;software is organized in such a way that “plugins” can be written for new&lt;br /&gt;document types. Plugins currently exist for plain text, HTML, Word, PDF, &lt;br /&gt;PostScript, E-mail, some proprietary formats, and for recursively &lt;br /&gt;traversing directory structures and compressed archives containing such&lt;br /&gt;documents. A collection may have source documents in different forms.&lt;br /&gt;In order to build browsing indexes from metadata, an analogous scheme&lt;br /&gt;of “classifiers” is used: classifiers create browsing indexes of various&lt;br /&gt;kinds based on metadata. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Designed for multi-&lt;br /&gt;gigabyte collections &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collections can contain millions of documents, making the Greenstone&lt;br /&gt;system suitable for collections up to several gigabytes. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Documents can be in &lt;br /&gt;any language &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unicode is used throughout the software, allowing any language to be&lt;br /&gt;processed in a consistent manner. To date, collections have been built&lt;br /&gt;containing French, Spanish, Maori, Chinese, Arabic and English. On-the-&lt;br /&gt;fly conversion is used to convert from Unicode to an alphabet supported&lt;br /&gt;by the user’s web browser. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;User interface &lt;br /&gt;available in multiple &lt;br /&gt;languages &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The interface can be presented in multiple languages. Currently, the&lt;br /&gt;interface is available in Arabic, Chinese, Dutch, English, French, German, &lt;br /&gt;Maori, Portuguese, and Spanish. New languages can be added easily. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collections can &lt;br /&gt;contain text, pictures, &lt;br /&gt;audio, and video &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greenstone collections can contain text, pictures, audio and video clips.&lt;br /&gt;Most non-textual material is either linked in to the textual documents or &lt;br /&gt;accompanied by textual descriptions (such as figure captions) to allow&lt;br /&gt;full-text searching and browsing. However, the architecture permits&lt;br /&gt;implementation of plugins and classifiers even for non-textual data. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Uses advanced &lt;br /&gt;compression &lt;br /&gt;techniques &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Compression techniques are used to reduce the size of the indexes and&lt;br /&gt;text. Reducing the size of the indexes via compression has the added&lt;br /&gt;advantage of increasing the speed of text retrieval. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;APPENDIX A—SOFTWARE FEATURES 77 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Administrative function &lt;br /&gt;provided &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;An “administrative” function enables specified users to authorize new&lt;br /&gt;users to build collections, protect documents so that they can only be&lt;br /&gt;accessed by registered users on presentation of a password, examine the&lt;br /&gt;composition of all collections, and so on. Logs of user activity can record &lt;br /&gt;all queries made to every Greenstone collection. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;New collections appear &lt;br /&gt;dynamically &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collections can be updated and new ones brought on-line at any time, &lt;br /&gt;without bringing the system down; the process responsible for the user &lt;br /&gt;interface will notice (through periodic polling) when new collections&lt;br /&gt;appear and add them to the list presented to the user. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collections can be &lt;br /&gt;published on the &lt;br /&gt;Internet or on CD-&lt;br /&gt;ROM &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The software can be used to serve collections over the World-Wide Web. &lt;br /&gt;Greenstone collections can be made available, in precisely the same form,&lt;br /&gt;on CD-ROM. The user interface is through a standard web browser&lt;br /&gt;(Netscape is provided on each disk), and the interaction is identical to&lt;br /&gt;accessing the collection on the web—except that response times are more &lt;br /&gt;predictable. The CD-ROMs run under all versions of the Windows &lt;br /&gt;operating system. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collections can be &lt;br /&gt;distributed amongst &lt;br /&gt;different computers &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A flexible process structure allows different collections to be served by &lt;br /&gt;different computers, yet be presented to the user in the same way, on the&lt;br /&gt;same web page, as part of the same digital library. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Operates on both &lt;br /&gt;Windows and Unix  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greenstone runs under both Windows (3.1/3.11, 95/98/Me, NT/2000) and&lt;br /&gt;Unix (Linux and SunOS). Any of these systems can be used as a &lt;br /&gt;webserver. Collections cannot be built on low-end Windows systems &lt;br /&gt;(3.1/3.11), but pre-built collections can be transferred to them. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;What you get with &lt;br /&gt;Greenstone  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Greenstone Digital Library is open-source software, available from &lt;br /&gt;the New Zealand Digital Library (nzdl.org) under the terms of the GNU&lt;br /&gt;General Public License. The software includes everything described&lt;br /&gt;above: web serving, CD-ROM creation, collection building, multi-lingual &lt;br /&gt;capability, plugins and classifiers for a variety of different source &lt;br /&gt;document types. It includes an autoinstall feature to allow easy&lt;br /&gt;installation on both Windows and Unix. In the spirit of open-source &lt;br /&gt;software, users are encouraged to contribute modifications and&lt;br /&gt;enhancements. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;78 APPENDIX A—SOFTWARE FEATURES &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;greenstone.org  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Appendix B &lt;br /&gt; Glossary of terms &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Term Meaning &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;autoconf Unix program used to configure the Greenstone software installation &lt;br /&gt;package to suit your system &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Autorun Windows feature that starts a program automatically whenever a CD-&lt;br /&gt;ROM is inserted &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Boolean query Query to an information retrieval system that may contain AND, OR, &lt;br /&gt;NOT &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Browsing Accessing a collection by scanning an organized list of metadata values &lt;br /&gt;associated with the documents (such as author, title, date, keywords) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;buildcol.pl Greenstone program used to build collections &lt;br /&gt;Building Process of creating the indexing and browsing structures that are used to &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;access a collection &lt;br /&gt;C++ Programming language in which the majority of the Greenstone software &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;is written &lt;br /&gt;Casefolding Making uppercase and lowercase words look the same, for searching &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;purposes &lt;br /&gt;CGI Common Gateway Interface, a scheme that allows users to activate &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;programs on the host computer by clicking on web pages &lt;br /&gt;CGI script Code associated with a button, menu, or link on a web page that specifies &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;what the host computer is to do when it is clicked &lt;br /&gt;cgi-bin Directory in which CGI scripts are stored &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Classifier Greenstone code module that examines document metadata to form an &lt;br /&gt;index for browsing  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collection Set of documents that are brought together under a uniform searching and &lt;br /&gt;browsing interface &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collection &lt;br /&gt;configuration file &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;File that specifies how a collection is to be imported and built, what &lt;br /&gt;indexes and language interfaces are to be provided, etc. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collection server Program responsible for providing access to a collection when it is being &lt;br /&gt;used &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;80 APPENDIX B—GLOSSARY OF TERMS &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Configuration file See collection configuration file, main configuration file, site &lt;br /&gt;configuration file &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;CVS Concurrent Versioning System, a scheme for maintaining source code &lt;br /&gt;used throughout Greenstone &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;db2txt Greenstone tool for viewing a GDBM database as text (see GDBM) &lt;br /&gt;Demo collection A subset of the Humanities Development Library, distributed with the &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greenstone software and used for illustration in this tutorial &lt;br /&gt;Digital library Collection of digital objects (text, audio, video), along with methods for &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;access and retrieval, and for selection, organization, and maintenance &lt;br /&gt;DL Development Library, A Greenstone collection of humanitarian &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;information for developing countries &lt;br /&gt;Document Basic unit from which digital library collections are constructed; it may &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;include text, graphics, sound, video, etc. &lt;br /&gt;Dublin core A standard way of describing metadata &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fast CGI Facility that allows CGI scripts to remain continuously active so that they &lt;br /&gt;do not have to be restarted from scratch every time they are invoked &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Filter program That part of a Greenstone collection server that implements querying and &lt;br /&gt;browsing operations  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Format string A string that specifies how documents and other listings are to be &lt;br /&gt;displayed in Greenstone &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;GB-encoding Standard way of encoding the Chinese language &lt;br /&gt;GDBM GNU DataBase Manager, a program used within the Greenstone software &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;to store metadata for each document &lt;br /&gt;GIMP GNU Image-Manipulation Program used (on Unix) to create icons in &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greenstone &lt;br /&gt;GML Greenstone Markup Language, an XML-compliant format used for &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;storing documents internally &lt;br /&gt;GNU license Software license that permits users to copy and distribute computer &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;programs freely, and modify them—so long as all modifications are made &lt;br /&gt;publicly available &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greenstone The name of this digital library software &lt;br /&gt;GSDL Abbreviation for Greenstone Digital Library &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;%GSDLHOME%  Operating system variable that represents the top-level directory in which &lt;br /&gt;all Greenstone programs and collections are stored ($GSDLHOME on &lt;br /&gt;Unix systems) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;%GSDLOS%  Operating system variable that represents the operating system currently &lt;br /&gt;being used ($GSDLOS on Unix systems) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;hashfile Greenstone program used at import or build time to generate the OID of &lt;br /&gt;each document &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;APPENDIX B—GLOSSARY OF TERMS 81 &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;HTML HyperText Markup Language, the language in which web documents are &lt;br /&gt;written &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;import.pl Greenstone program used to import documents &lt;br /&gt;Importing Process of bringing collections of documents into the Greenstone system &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Index Information structure that is used for searching or browsing a collection &lt;br /&gt;InstallShield Windows program, used by Greenstone CD-ROMs, that allows a system &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;to be installed from a CD-ROM  &lt;br /&gt;Main configuration &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;file &lt;br /&gt;File that contains specifications common to all collections served by this &lt;br /&gt;site &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Metadata Descriptive data such as author, title, date, keywords, and so on, that is &lt;br /&gt;associated with a document (or document collection) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;MG Managing Gigabytes, a program used by the Greenstone system for full-&lt;br /&gt;text indexing, that incorporates compression techniques (see Witten, I.H., &lt;br /&gt;Moffat, A. and Bell, T. Managing Gigabytes: compressing and indexing &lt;br /&gt;documents and images, Morgan Kaufmann, second edition, 1999) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;mgbuild MG program for building a compressed full-text index &lt;br /&gt;mgquery MG program for querying a compressed full-text index &lt;br /&gt;mkcol.pl Greenstone program that creates and initializes the directory structure for &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;a new collection &lt;br /&gt;New Zealand  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Digital Library &lt;br /&gt;Project &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Research project in the Computer Science Department at the University of &lt;br /&gt;Waikato, New Zealand, that created the Greenstone software (nzdl.org) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;OID Object Identifier, a unique identification code associated with a document&lt;br /&gt;Perl Programming language used for many of the text-processing operations &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;that occur during the building process &lt;br /&gt;Ping Message sent to a system to determine whether it is running or not &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plugin Code module for handling documents of different formats, used during &lt;br /&gt;the importing and building processes &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Protocol Set of conventions by which a Greenstone receptionist communicates &lt;br /&gt;with a collection server &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ranked query Natural-language query to an information retrieval system, for which the &lt;br /&gt;documents that match the query are sorted in order of relevance  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Receptionist Program that organizes the Greenstone user interface &lt;br /&gt;RTF Rich Text Format, a standard format for interchange of text documents &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Searching Accessing a collection through a full-text search of its contents (or parts &lt;br /&gt;of contents, such as section titles) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Server See Collection server and Web server &lt;br /&gt;setup.bat, setup.sh, &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;setup.csh &lt;br /&gt;Script used to set up your environment to recognize the Greenstone &lt;br /&gt;software &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;82 APPENDIX B—GLOSSARY OF TERMS &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Site configuration &lt;br /&gt;file &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;File that contains specifications used to configure the Greenstone &lt;br /&gt;software for the site on which it is installed &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stemming Stripping endings off a query term to make it more general &lt;br /&gt;STL Standard template library, a widely-available library of C++ code &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;developed by Silicon Graphics &lt;br /&gt;txt2db Greenstone program used at build time to create the GDBM database &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unicode Standard scheme for representing the character sets used in the world’s &lt;br /&gt;languages &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;UNU The United Nations University; also used to refer to a Greenstone &lt;br /&gt;collection created for that organization &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Web server Standard program that computers use to make information accessible over &lt;br /&gt;the World Wide Web &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;XML A standard format for structured documents and data on the web (the &lt;br /&gt;Greenstone Markup Language is an XML-compliant format) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</Content>
</Section>
</Archive>
