<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE Archive SYSTEM "http://greenstone.org/dtd/Archive/1.0/Archive.dtd">
<Archive>
<Section>
  <Description>
    <Metadata name="gsdldoctype">indexed_doc</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Language">en</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Encoding">utf8</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Title">ReadingaComputerScienceResearchPaper</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="URL">http://C:/Program Files/Greenstone/tmp/F755.html</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="UTF8URL">http://C:/Program Files/Greenstone/tmp/F755.html</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="gsdlsourcefilename">import\inroads2009.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="gsdlconvertedfilename">C:\Program Files\Greenstone\tmp\F755.html</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="OrigSource">F755.html</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Source">inroads2009.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="SourceFile">inroads2009.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Plugin">PDFPlugin</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="FileSize">82546</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="FilenameRoot">inroads2009</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="FileFormat">PDF</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="srcicon">_iconpdf_</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="srclink_file">doc.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="srclinkFile">doc.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="NumPages">6</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="dc.Creator">oo</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="dc.Subject">ict</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="dc.Title">inroads2009.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="dls.Organization">Mathematics and ICT|Mathematics|Moodle</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.ExifTool.ExifToolVersion">8.57</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.Directory">C:\Program Files\Greenstone\collect\ebook\import</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FileModifyDate">2018:12:10 02:50:42-08:00</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FileName">inroads2009.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FilePermissions">666</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FileSize">82546</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FileType">PDF</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.MIMEType">application/pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.CreateDate">2009:06:20 11:21:09-06:00</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.Creator">LaTeX with hyperref package</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.Linearized">false</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.ModifyDate">2009:06:20 11:21:09-06:00</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.PDFVersion">1.4</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.PageCount">6</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.PageMode">UseOutlines</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.Producer">dvips + GPL Ghostscript 8.64</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.About">4b22bd90-95db-11e9-0000-b76f7fbc8aa9</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.CreateDate">2009:06:20 11:21:09-06:00</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.Creator">LaTeX with hyperref package</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.CreatorTool">LaTeX with hyperref package</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.DocumentID">4b22bd90-95db-11e9-0000-b76f7fbc8aa9</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.Format">application/pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.ModifyDate">2009:06:20 11:21:09-06:00</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.Producer">dvips + GPL Ghostscript 8.64</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.XMPToolkit">XMP toolkit 2.9.1-13&amp;#44; framework 1.6</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Identifier">HASH0173f1382805b0c8d4b06bd4</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="lastmodified">1544439042</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="lastmodifieddate">20181210</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="oailastmodified">1545141408</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="oailastmodifieddate">20181218</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="assocfilepath">HASH0173.dir</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="gsdlassocfile">doc.pdf:application/pdf:</Metadata>
  </Description>
  <Content>
&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reading a Computer Science Research Paper&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Philip W. L. Fong&lt;br /&gt;Department of Computer Science&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;University of Calgary&lt;br /&gt;Calgary, Alberta, Canada T2N 1N4&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;pwlfong@cpsc.ucalgary.ca&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;(To appear in Inroads, the SIGCSE Bulletin, 2009)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial article highlights some points that a graduate or senior undergrad-&lt;br /&gt;uate student should bear in mind when reading a computer science research paper.&lt;br /&gt;Specifically, the reading process is divided into three tasks: comprehension, evaluation&lt;br /&gt;and synthesis. The genre of paper review is then introduced as a vehicle for critical&lt;br /&gt;reading of research papers. Lastly, guidelines on how to be initiated into the trade of&lt;br /&gt;conference and/or journal paper review are given.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Designed to be used in a graduate course setting, this tutorial comes with a sug-&lt;br /&gt;gested marking scheme for grading paper reviews with a comprehension-evaluation-&lt;br /&gt;synthesis structure.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 Comprehension&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first lesson to reading research papers is learning to understand what a paper says. A&lt;br /&gt;common pitfall for a beginner is to focus solely on the technicalities. Yes, technical contents&lt;br /&gt;are very important, but they are in no way the only focus of a careful reading. In general,&lt;br /&gt;you should ask yourself the following four questions when you are reading a research paper.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. What is the research problem the paper attempts to address? What is the&lt;br /&gt;motivation of the research work? Is there a crisis in the research field that the paper&lt;br /&gt;attempts to resolve? Is the research work attempting to overcome the weaknesses of&lt;br /&gt;existing approaches? Is an existing research paradigm challenged? In short, what is&lt;br /&gt;the niche of the paper?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. What are the claimed contributions of the paper? What is new in this paper?&lt;br /&gt;A new question is asked? A new understanding of the research problem? A new&lt;br /&gt;methodology for solving problems? A new algorithm? A new breed of software tools or&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;systems? A new experimental method? A new proof technique? A new formalism or&lt;br /&gt;notation? A new evidence to substantiate or disprove a previously published claim?&lt;br /&gt;A new research area? In short, what is innovative about this paper?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;3. How do the authors substantiate their claims? What is themethodology adopted&lt;br /&gt;to substantiate the claims? What is the argument of the paper? What are the major&lt;br /&gt;theorems? What experiments are conducted? Data analyses? Simulations? Bench-&lt;br /&gt;marks? User studies? Case studies? Examples? In short, what makes the claims&lt;br /&gt;scientific (as opposed to being mere opinions1)?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;4. What are the conclusions? What have we learned from the paper? Shall the&lt;br /&gt;standard practice of the field be changed as a result of the new findings? Is the result&lt;br /&gt;generalizable? Can the result be applied to other areas of the field? What are the open&lt;br /&gt;problems? In short, what are the lessons one can learn from the paper?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every well-written research paper contains an abstract, which is a summary of the paper.&lt;br /&gt;The role of an abstract is to outline the answers to the above questions. Look therefore, first&lt;br /&gt;to the abstract for answers. The paper should be an elaboration of the abstract.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another way of looking at paper reading is that every good paper tells a story. Conse-&lt;br /&gt;quently, when you read a paper, ask yourself, “What is the plot?” The four questions listed&lt;br /&gt;above make up an archetypical plot structure for every research paper.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;2 Evaluation&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;An integral component of scholarship is to be critical of scientific claims. Ambitious claims&lt;br /&gt;are usually easy to make but difficult to substantiate. Solid scholarship involves careful&lt;br /&gt;validation of scientific claims. Reading research papers is therefore an exercise of critical&lt;br /&gt;thinking.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. Is the research problem significant? Is the work scratching minor itches? Are the&lt;br /&gt;authors solving artificial problems (aka straw man)? Does the work enable practical&lt;br /&gt;applications , deepen understanding , or explore new design space?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. Are the contributions significant? Is the paper worth reading? Are the authors&lt;br /&gt;simply repeating the state of the art? Are there real surprises? Are the authors aware of&lt;br /&gt;the relation of their work to existing literature2? Is the paper addressing a well-known&lt;br /&gt;open problem?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1Alternatively, what makes it a research paper rather than a science fiction?&lt;br /&gt;2Be very sceptical of work that is so “novel” that it bears no relation to any existing work, builds upon&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;no existing paradigm, and yet addresses a research problem so significant that it promises to transform the&lt;br /&gt;world. Such are the signs that the author might not be aware of existing literature on the topic. In such a&lt;br /&gt;case, the authors could very well be repeating works that have already been done decades ago&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;3. Are the claims valid? Have the authors been cutting corners (intentionally or un-&lt;br /&gt;intentionally)? Has the right theorem been proven? Errors in proofs? Problematic&lt;br /&gt;experimental setup? Confounding factors? Unrealistic, artificial benchmarks? Com-&lt;br /&gt;paring apples and oranges? Methodological misunderstanding? Do the numbers add&lt;br /&gt;up? Are generalizations valid? Are the claims modest enough3?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you evaluate a research work, two caveats are worth noting:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Consistently evaluating research works in a negative way gives a young researcher&lt;br /&gt;a false sense of being critical. Learn to be fair: attend to both the strengths and&lt;br /&gt;weaknesses of the work. If you are reading a classical paper that has been published&lt;br /&gt;for a while, make sure you are reading the paper in the right historical context: What&lt;br /&gt;seems to be obvious now might have been ground-breaking then.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• A young researcher may want to focus on point 3 (Are the claims valid?). Evaluating&lt;br /&gt;the significance of the research problem and the contributions of the paper usually&lt;br /&gt;requires a comprehensive understanding of the research field as a whole. Yet, do not&lt;br /&gt;let the above comment hinder you from disagreeing with the paper authors in matters&lt;br /&gt;of significance.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;3 Synthesis&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Creativity does not arise from the void. Interacting with the scholarly community through&lt;br /&gt;reading reseach papers is one of the most effective ways for generating novel research agendas.&lt;br /&gt;When you read a research paper, you should see it as an opportunity for you to come up&lt;br /&gt;with new research projects. The following is a list of questions you can ask to help in this&lt;br /&gt;direction. (Of course, this list is not supposed to be exhaustive.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• What is the crux of the research problem?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• What are some alternative approaches to address the research problem?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Is there an alternative way to substantiate the claim of the authors?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• What is a good argument against the case made by the authors?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Can the research results be strengthened?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Can the research results be applied to another context?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• What are the open problems raised by this work?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Bottom line: If you were to do the research, how would you do differently?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;3It is very tempting for an inexperienced researcher to make overly general conclusion from limited&lt;br /&gt;evidence. A high quality scientific claim is always modest — claiming only what can be concluded from the&lt;br /&gt;evidence, making explicit the limitation of the evidence, and carefully delimiting the scope of the claim.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;4 Paper Review&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A paper review is a short essay (5 pages, single-space) reporting what you have learned from&lt;br /&gt;reading a research paper. Writing reviews for the papers you have read is a great way to&lt;br /&gt;sharpen your paper reading skills. Such a review is typically structured in three sections —&lt;br /&gt;summary , critique, and synthesis .&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. Summary. Give a brief summary of the work in your own words . This section&lt;br /&gt;demonstrates your understanding of the paper, and as such it should answer the four&lt;br /&gt;questions outlined in Section 1. The summary section should be structured as follows:&lt;br /&gt;(1) motivation, (2) contribution, (3) methodology and/or argument, and (4) conclusion.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is imperative that you use your own words to summarize the paper. Failing to&lt;br /&gt;adhere to this guideline not only constitutes plagarism, but also demonstrates that&lt;br /&gt;you probably do not quite understand the work. You can be sure that you understand&lt;br /&gt;something only when you are capable of explaining it in your own words.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. Critique. Pick two to three points4 you want to argue with the authors5. Use the&lt;br /&gt;questions outlined in Section 2 to help you come up with meaningful critiques.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do not repeat the Limitations section of the paper. Doing so means that you agree&lt;br /&gt;with the authors! Pick points of disagreement, and launch an intellectual debate with&lt;br /&gt;the authors. Carefully articulate and substantiate your case. Do not just say, “I don’t&lt;br /&gt;like this point.” Instead, give technical reasons to substantiate your critiques.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Be specific in your choice of words. Avoid generic adjectives such as “bad”, “poor”,&lt;br /&gt;“lame”, “stupid”, etc, and their synonyms and antonyms. You can go a lot fur-&lt;br /&gt;ther by replacing such vague words with more specific ones: “inelegant”, “inefficient”,&lt;br /&gt;“memory-intensive”, “ill-defined”, etc.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;3. Synthesis. Propose one to two ways in which the research work can be further devel-&lt;br /&gt;oped. Do not repeat the Future Work section of the paper. Be original. Consult the&lt;br /&gt;list of questions in Section 3 if you run out of ideas.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I use this format when I ask students in my graduate classes to review a paper. Consult the&lt;br /&gt;Appendix for a sample outline, a marking scheme, and page length suggestions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;4This restriction on the number of critiques is intentional. Firstly, the restriction forces you to pinpoint&lt;br /&gt;the major weaknesses of the paper, rather than to spend efforts debating issues of peripheral importance.&lt;br /&gt;Secondly, such a restriction allows you to enjoy the mental room necessary for developing a substantial case&lt;br /&gt;against the authors.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;5Notice that the Critique section presents only negative evaluations of the paper. Have we forgotten&lt;br /&gt;about being fair to a research work? No, positive evaluations are omitted for a good reason. Experience&lt;br /&gt;tells us that students tend to give positive evaluation in the following form: “I agree with the authors. They&lt;br /&gt;did this and that, and they did a good job.” The end result is usually a repetition of the authors’ claims. I&lt;br /&gt;find that focusing on critiques offers a more substantial learning experience to the students, forcing them to&lt;br /&gt;think rather than to parrot.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;5 An Alternative Review Format&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The format of paper review outlined in the previous section is the one I adopt for my graduate&lt;br /&gt;classes. It works for me, but it is definitely not the only way to structure a paper review. I&lt;br /&gt;outline here an alternative format I learned from a friend of mine.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. What is the purpose of the work?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. How do the authors achieve this purpose? Why is this particular approach adopted?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;3. Do you think the purpose has been achieved?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;4. What insights have you gained from reading this work?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Notice the parallel between this alternative structure and the summary-critique-synthesis&lt;br /&gt;structure in the previous section.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;6 Reading Like a Pro&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When a research paper is submitted to a conference or a journal, it will undergo a peer&lt;br /&gt;review process, in which the paper is subject to the intense scrutiny of peer researchers. The&lt;br /&gt;referees who review the submitted paper will read the paper in more or less the same way as&lt;br /&gt;we outlined in Sections 1 and 2, and then they will write up a referee report in a style similar&lt;br /&gt;to the paper review discussed in Section 4, except for the synthesis section. Based on the&lt;br /&gt;referee reports, the program chair of a conference or the editor of a journal will then make&lt;br /&gt;the decision of whether to accept the paper. It is therefore instructional to understand how&lt;br /&gt;a referee go about reviewing a paper, and learn to read research papers like a professional.&lt;br /&gt;A very good introduction to the subject can be found in an article by Smith [2]. The paper&lt;br /&gt;is slanted towards experimental computer science. For a perspective focusing on theoretical&lt;br /&gt;computer science, consult the article by Parberry [1]. After reading these papers, I highly&lt;br /&gt;recommend graduate students to find opportunities to practice professional paper reviewing.&lt;br /&gt;Your supervisor will likely be involved in the program committees of conferences, or asked&lt;br /&gt;to review papers for conferences. Approach your thesis supervisors, and volunteer to help&lt;br /&gt;out with paper reviews. By actually writing up a professional review report, and discussing&lt;br /&gt;your review with your supervisor, you will gain tremendous insight into the paper publishing&lt;br /&gt;process, as well as the implicit value system of the academic world. This kind of training is&lt;br /&gt;hard to acquire through other means.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;References&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;[1] Ian Parberry. A guide for new referees in theoretical computer science. Information and&lt;br /&gt;Computation, 112(1):96–116, July 1994.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] Alan Jay Smith. The task of the referee. IEEE Computer, 23(4):65–71, April 1990.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Sample Outline of a Paper Review&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Review: Title of Paper being Reviewed&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Author of this Review&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Other information such as student ID&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 Summary (40% : 2.5 pages)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1.1 Motivation (8%)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1.2 Contribution (8%)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1.3 Methodology (16%)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1.4 Conclusion (8%)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;2 Critique (30% : 1.5 pages)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;2.1 Title of 1st Critique (15%)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;2.2 Title of 2nd Critique (15%)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;2.3 Optional: Title of 3rd Critique&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If a 3rd critique is given, then each critique is worth 10%.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;3 Synthesis (30% : 1 page)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;3.1 Title of 1st Idea (30%)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;3.2 Optional: Title of 2nd Idea&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If a 2nd idea is presented, then each idea is worth 15%.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</Content>
</Section>
</Archive>
