<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE Archive SYSTEM "http://greenstone.org/dtd/Archive/1.0/Archive.dtd">
<Archive>
<Section>
  <Description>
    <Metadata name="gsdldoctype">indexed_doc</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Language">en</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Encoding">utf8</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Title">Mekelle University – Mekelle Institute of Technology BSC Thesis Report Writing...</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="URL">http://C:/Program Files/Greenstone/tmp/F231.html</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="UTF8URL">http://C:/Program Files/Greenstone/tmp/F231.html</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="gsdlsourcefilename">import\Thesis Writing Guidline.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="gsdlconvertedfilename">C:\Program Files\Greenstone\tmp\F231.html</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="OrigSource">F231.html</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Source">Thesis Writing Guidline.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="SourceFile">Thesis Writing Guidline.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Plugin">PDFPlugin</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="FileSize">130001</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="FilenameRoot">Thesis Writing Guidline</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="FileFormat">PDF</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="srcicon">_iconpdf_</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="srclink_file">doc.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="srclinkFile">doc.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="NumPages">3</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.ExifTool.ExifToolVersion">8.57</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.Directory">C:\Program Files\Greenstone\collect\ebook\import</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FileModifyDate">2018:12:10 02:51:06-08:00</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FileName">Thesis Writing Guidline.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FilePermissions">666</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FileSize">130001</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FileType">PDF</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.MIMEType">application/pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.Author">Vostro 2520</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.Company">Microsoft</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.CreateDate">2016:05:03 16:54:35+03:00</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.Creator">Vostro 2520</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.Linearized">true</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.ModifyDate">2016:05:03 16:54:43+03:00</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.PDFVersion">1.5</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.PageCount">3</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.PageLayout">OneColumn</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.Producer">Adobe PDF Library 9.0</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.SourceModified">D:20160503135010</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.TaggedPDF">true</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.Company">Microsoft</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.CreateDate">2016:05:03 16:54:35+03:00</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.Creator">Vostro 2520</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.CreatorTool">Acrobat PDFMaker 9.0 for Word</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.DocumentID">uuid:5fa93bdd-efb9-4769-b746-7a75ea31eddc</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.Format">application/pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.InstanceID">uuid:045148eb-1e2c-43b3-a508-b5a96011d21a</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.MetadataDate">2016:05:03 16:54:43+03:00</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.ModifyDate">2016:05:03 16:54:43+03:00</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.Producer">Adobe PDF Library 9.0</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.SourceModified">D:20160503135010</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.Subject">2</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.XMPToolkit">Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c041 52.342996&amp;#44; 2008/05/07-20:48:00</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Identifier">HASH012d6b8274156bdfc6dc31c8</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="lastmodified">1544439066</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="lastmodifieddate">20181210</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="oailastmodified">1545141386</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="oailastmodifieddate">20181218</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="assocfilepath">HASH012d.dir</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="gsdlassocfile">doc.pdf:application/pdf:</Metadata>
  </Description>
  <Content>
&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mekelle University – Mekelle Institute of Technology  &lt;br /&gt;BSC Thesis  Report Writing Guideline  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mekelle University  -  Mekelle Institute of Technology  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Your thesis is the most important part of your study. Therefore, you should give special priority and &lt;br /&gt;be hard worker as it is so important for your future career. Writing what you have done in your &lt;br /&gt;thesis work may be even harder than the actual work, especially for beginners. Knowing this fact &lt;br /&gt;may help you not to submit hasty and poorly written thesis reports. Remember that thesis report &lt;br /&gt;format /content may slightly differ from university to university thought it plays the same role, i.e. &lt;br /&gt;to present your work in a clear, transparent and elaborate way. In this guide line, we will briefly see &lt;br /&gt;the contents of your thesis report and what you should write in each section of the report during &lt;br /&gt;your thesis work in MU-MIT. Departments and advisors can slightly modify the template according &lt;br /&gt;to their specific needs. However, the core contents of  a thesis report should comply with this &lt;br /&gt;guideline (template). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thesis Report Writing Guideline &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; Your thesis report must contain the following sections in order: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;1. Title  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. Abstract  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;3. Acknowledgement (optional)  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;4. Table of contents  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;5. List of figures (optional)  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;6. List of acronyms or abbreviations (optional)  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;7. List of Tables (optional)  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;8. Introduction  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;9. Background and Related work  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;10. Design and Implementation  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;11. Results and Discussions  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;12. Conclusions  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;13. Future work (optional)  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;14. References  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;15. Appendices (optional)  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;2 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mekelle University – Mekelle Institute of Technology  &lt;br /&gt;BSC Thesis  Report Writing Guideline  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The contents of some of the sections (listed above) are described as follows.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. Abstract &lt;br /&gt;The purpose of an abstract is to give the reader a good summary of what the thesis is about and &lt;br /&gt;the major results or findings. In abstract, answers to the following questions must be compiled &lt;br /&gt;in a single paragraph: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• What is the thesis about? :  Briefly describe the area of study. You can start with “The &lt;br /&gt;thesis focuses on analysis of / investigation of / design of / study of …….. “ &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• What problem are you trying to solve/ why are you doing it? :  include a brief &lt;br /&gt;summary of the problem statement and point out the main objectives of the thesis.  But &lt;br /&gt;be careful not to write more than expected here. A more detailed problem statement &lt;br /&gt;and motivation are expected to be written in the introduction section. Further details &lt;br /&gt;regarding significance of your work is expected be explained in the background section &lt;br /&gt;(after literature review).  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• What did you do and how did you do it? Briefly mention the main tasks you have done, &lt;br /&gt;and briefly explain the methods, tools (for example MATLAB), and assumptions (or &lt;br /&gt;models) you have used to do your thesis. (For example: “ A closed-form mathematical &lt;br /&gt;expression of the system has been obtained and simulation is done in MATLAB”). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• What are the major results of your thesis? Explain the major results, findings, and &lt;br /&gt;implications of your results in maximum of two or three sentences.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. Introduction  &lt;br /&gt;Introduction is all about what a reader can expect in the document, in a concise manner. &lt;br /&gt;However, the introduction contains all the major points that are actually covered in the &lt;br /&gt;document.  Introduction is like showing a trailer (advertisement)  of a movie to entice a reader &lt;br /&gt;to go through the entire document.  The points that must be covered in introduction are () &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Brief introduction and description of the area of study  &lt;br /&gt;• Problem statement of the thesis (in more detail than what you wrote in the abstract). In &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;this part, try to explain what existing problem motivates you to undertake the research/ &lt;br /&gt;project, and why is it worthy solving the problem.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Objective of the thesis /project: explain the goals of the project in detail.    &lt;br /&gt;• Brief explanation of how you solved the problem and the main tasks you have done &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that, in this case, it may be similar to what you wrote in the abstract. Try to write it &lt;br /&gt;in different way, in a way the reader attracts more. However, it is not really a problem if &lt;br /&gt;it is similar to the abstract. Because the abstract is considered to be a separate &lt;br /&gt;document and must include summary of the whole thesis report.  &lt;br /&gt;Example: “ a mathematical derivation of …… has been obtained  and simulation is done &lt;br /&gt;in MATLAB” or “a web based application has been implemented  using …..” ). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;•   Scope of the thesis: describe what will and will not be included in your study. &lt;br /&gt;• A verbal “table of contents” of what lies ahead: introduce briefly the next chapters. For &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;example, “The rest of the document is organized as follows: chapter 2 explains ……, &lt;br /&gt;chapter 3 deals with …….”.   &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;3 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mekelle University – Mekelle Institute of Technology  &lt;br /&gt;BSC Thesis  Report Writing Guideline  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;3. Background   &lt;br /&gt;The purpose of background is to explain the area of your study in detail and (in later part of it) &lt;br /&gt;convince the reader that you are familiar with incidents leading up to the study.  It is also &lt;br /&gt;important to provide definitions for terminology that may not be familiar to your reader.  In &lt;br /&gt;general, in the background, you should include the following points: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Sufficient background of the area of study: describe where the problem originates in &lt;br /&gt;detail  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Definition of terminologies and explanation of concepts that may not be familiar to the &lt;br /&gt;reader (for example for your junior students). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Proper acknowledgement of the previous work on which you are building (literature &lt;br /&gt;review): convince the reader that you are familiar with current studies by showing &lt;br /&gt;sufficient and up-to-date references which are closely related to your topic.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Motivation:  compare the related work or how others tried to solve similar problems &lt;br /&gt;(from literature review) with your work and show that your work is significant and fills a &lt;br /&gt;gap in the field.  In standard researches, this part examines the contribution of a &lt;br /&gt;research work in the field. It may be hard for you to point out the newness and &lt;br /&gt;contribution of your thesis work. However, you have to explain the reason why you are &lt;br /&gt;doing your thesis on the selected topic anyway.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;4. System Design and implementation  &lt;br /&gt;Show your methods and designs how you solved the problem. You may use mathematical &lt;br /&gt;models or algorithms to represent your solution.  Depending on your work, this section may &lt;br /&gt;have different subsections.  For example:  requirement analysis, detailed design procedures, &lt;br /&gt;mathematical analyses/derivations, testing the system or prototype, etc.  . &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;5. Results and  discussions  &lt;br /&gt;Provide the results (for example in the form of graphs) and explain their implications. What do &lt;br /&gt;your results imply?  If possible, discuss on your results by comparing with previous works &lt;br /&gt;(similar results), which is called “Result Validation”.   &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;6. Conclusions   &lt;br /&gt;• Draw major themes of the thesis.  &lt;br /&gt;• Relate the result with the problem statement in the introduction section (Have you &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;solved the problem?) &lt;br /&gt;• What other implication have drawn from your thesis?  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;7. Future work and recommendations (optional) &lt;br /&gt;May be because of lack of time or material, is there anything you recommend to be done in this &lt;br /&gt;area which you did not? What other recommendations do you have? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;8. References  &lt;br /&gt;9. Appendices  (optional) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</Content>
</Section>
</Archive>
