<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE Archive SYSTEM "http://greenstone.org/dtd/Archive/1.0/Archive.dtd">
<Archive>
<Section>
  <Description>
    <Metadata name="gsdldoctype">indexed_doc</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Language">en</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Encoding">utf8</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Title">Microsoft Word - Literature Reviews</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="URL">http://C:/Program Files/Greenstone/tmp/F102.html</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="UTF8URL">http://C:/Program Files/Greenstone/tmp/F102.html</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="gsdlsourcefilename">import\literaturereviews.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="gsdlconvertedfilename">C:\Program Files\Greenstone\tmp\F102.html</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="OrigSource">F102.html</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Source">literaturereviews.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="SourceFile">literaturereviews.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Plugin">PDFPlugin</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="FileSize">207084</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="FilenameRoot">literaturereviews</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="FileFormat">PDF</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="srcicon">_iconpdf_</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="srclink_file">doc.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="srclinkFile">doc.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="NumPages">6</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="dc.Creator">ee</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="dc.Subject">english</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="dls.Organization">Mathematics and ICT|ICT|Moodle</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.ExifTool.ExifToolVersion">8.57</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.Directory">C:\Program Files\Greenstone\collect\ebook\import</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FileModifyDate">2018:12:10 02:50:50-08:00</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FileName">literaturereviews.pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FilePermissions">666</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FileSize">207084</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.FileType">PDF</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.File.MIMEType">application/pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.Author">ac333</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.CreateDate">2014:10:23 14:55:53Z</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.Creator">ac333</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.Linearized">true</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.ModifyDate">2014:10:27 13:21:46Z</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.PDFVersion">1.4</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.PageCount">6</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.Producer">AFPL Ghostscript 8.53</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.PDF.Title">Microsoft Word - Literature Reviews</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.CreateDate">2014:10:23 14:55:53Z</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.Creator">ac333</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.CreatorTool">PScript5.dll Version 5.2.2</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.DocumentID">uuid:6b8d04c3-22bb-4c17-86cf-04337bd05c7c</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.Format">application/pdf</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.InstanceID">uuid:60c9dc82-02ac-463f-9ee4-f374ec14d94e</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.MetadataDate">2014:10:27 13:21:46Z</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.ModifyDate">2014:10:27 13:21:46Z</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.Producer">AFPL Ghostscript 8.53</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.Title">Microsoft Word - Literature Reviews</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="ex.XMP.XMPToolkit">Adobe XMP Core 5.4-c005 78.147326&amp;#44; 2012/08/23-13:03:03</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="Identifier">HASH01d6751a9a65d087232b4ba0</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="lastmodified">1544439050</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="lastmodifieddate">20181210</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="oailastmodified">1545141410</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="oailastmodifieddate">20181218</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="assocfilepath">HASH01d6.dir</Metadata>
    <Metadata name="gsdlassocfile">doc.pdf:application/pdf:</Metadata>
  </Description>
  <Content>
&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;www.kent.ac.uk/learning &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Literature Reviews &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;3. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;4. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;5. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;6. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;7. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;8. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is a Literature Review? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Choosing Material &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Searching for Good Material &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assessing the Literature &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developing the Literature Review &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Placing the Literature Review in the Dissertation/Thesis &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Structuring the Literature Review &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Writing Up the Literature Review &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. What is a Literature Review? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; A literature review is simply a summary of what existing scholarship knows &lt;br /&gt;about a particular topic. It is always based on secondary sources – that is, what &lt;br /&gt;other people have already written on the subject; it is not concerned about &lt;br /&gt;discovering new knowledge or information. As such, it is a prelude to further &lt;br /&gt;research, a digest of scholarly opinion. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A literature review should focus only on the relevant academic literature: &lt;br /&gt;popular or non-academic sources may be brought in occasionally to illustrate a &lt;br /&gt;point, but the central interest is always on the data collected or the theories put &lt;br /&gt;together by recognised experts in the field.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A literature review will try to look at as much of this existing research as &lt;br /&gt;possible. It will review major scholarly books in the relevant area, but will also &lt;br /&gt;take a keen interest in journal articles, which in many subjects give more up-to-&lt;br /&gt;date material.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Preparing a literature review thus involves: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Searching for reliable, accurate and up-to-date material on the topic or subject &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Reading and summarising the key points from this literature &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Synthesising these key ideas, theories and concepts into a summary of what is &lt;br /&gt;known &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Discussing and evaluating these ideas, theories and concepts &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Identifying particular areas of debate or controversy &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Preparing the ground for the application of these ideas to new research &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;www.kent.ac.uk/learning &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. Choosing Material &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; Ask yourself questions such as these: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. What is the specific question, topic or focus for my assignment? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. What kind of material do I need? Theory? Methodology? Policy? &lt;br /&gt;Empirical data?  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;3. What type of literature is available (e.g., journals, books, government &lt;br /&gt;documents)?  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;4. What kind of literature is particularly authoritative in this academic &lt;br /&gt;discipline (e.g. psychology, sociology, pharmacy)? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;5. Has my search been wide enough to ensure I have identified all the &lt;br /&gt;relevant material?  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;6. On the other hand, has the search been narrow enough to exclude &lt;br /&gt;irrelevant material?  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;7. Is there a good enough sample of literature for the level (Ph.D, Master’s, &lt;br /&gt;undergraduate) of my dissertation or thesis?  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;8. Have I considered as many alternative points of view as possible? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;9. Will the reader find my literature review relevant, appropriate, and &lt;br /&gt;useful? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;3. Searching for Good Material &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; Make sure that all the literature you review is as up-to-date as possible. The &lt;br /&gt;sole exception would be ‘classic texts’ such as major works written by the &lt;br /&gt;leading scholars setting out formative ideas and theories central to your &lt;br /&gt;subject. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A good literature review will have a good range of material setting out as many &lt;br /&gt;different perspectives as possible. Try to get a good balance between &lt;br /&gt;substantial academic books and more recent journal articles. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A good place to start is with a bibliography. For undergraduate dissertations, &lt;br /&gt;look first at the bibliography provided with the module documentation. Choose &lt;br /&gt;one or two likely looking books or articles and then scan through the &lt;br /&gt;bibliographies provided by these authors. Skim read some of this material &lt;br /&gt;looking for clues: can you use these leads to identify key theories and authors &lt;br /&gt;or track down other appropriate material? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another approach is to try entering a few keywords into library catalogue &lt;br /&gt;search engines. You will almost certainly have to try a range of different words &lt;br /&gt;to capture as many items as possible. But avoid over-generalisations: if you &lt;br /&gt;type in something as broad as ‘social theory’ you are likely to get several &lt;br /&gt;thousand results! Try to be specific: for example, ‘Heidegger, existentialism’. &lt;br /&gt;Ideally, you should narrow the field down so you get just a few dozen results. &lt;br /&gt;Skim through these quickly to identity texts which are most likely to be helpful. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If this does not produce enough material, browse along the library shelves in &lt;br /&gt;the relevant subject area and look at any of the books that catch your eye. &lt;br /&gt;Check the contents and index pages to see if they are likely to help; if not, put &lt;br /&gt;the book back and try again.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;You could also ask one of the subject librarians for further help. Your &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;www.kent.ac.uk/learning &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;supervisor might be able to point you in the direction of some of the important &lt;br /&gt;literature, though remember this is your literature search, not theirs! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;For recent journal articles you will almost certainly need to use one of the &lt;br /&gt;online search engines. These can be found on the ‘Indexing Services’ button &lt;br /&gt;on the Templeman Library website.Kent students based at Medway still need &lt;br /&gt;to use the Templeman pages to access online journals, although you can get &lt;br /&gt;to these pages through the Drill Hall Library catalogue. Take a look as well at &lt;br /&gt;the Subject Guides on both the Templeman and DHL websites. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is no answer to the question ‘how many books and journal articles &lt;br /&gt;should I review?’ It all depends on the length of the dissertation, the nature of &lt;br /&gt;the subject, the focal point of interest, the level of study (undergraduate, &lt;br /&gt;Masters, Ph.D) and so on. Obviously, if your dissertation is going to be mostly &lt;br /&gt;an interaction with existing scholarship you need a longer literature review than &lt;br /&gt;if your subject involves new empirical research. Nor are you expected to know &lt;br /&gt;about everything written on your subject, especially at undergraduate level.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The key point is that you should aim to use the literature review to set out the &lt;br /&gt;boundaries of existing knowledge in your chosen area: what have other &lt;br /&gt;important scholars already said about this subject? Watch out for the obvious &lt;br /&gt;gaps! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, how many books and articles? Enough! Maybe – as a very rough and &lt;br /&gt;ready rule of thumb – 8-10 significant pieces (books and/or articles) for a 8,000 &lt;br /&gt;word dissertation, up to 20 major pieces of work for 12-15,000 words, and so &lt;br /&gt;on. But use your judgement! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;4. Assessing the Literature &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Skim through the books and articles identified as potentially relevant. Focus &lt;br /&gt;particularly on obvious ‘helps’ such as chapter summaries, journal abstracts, &lt;br /&gt;and even the index. Look for clues: how will this piece of literature contribute to &lt;br /&gt;your study (if at all)? If the answer is ‘not much’ then choose something &lt;br /&gt;different. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now re-read the chosen material carefully. Look especially for: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. The key point discussed by the author: is this clearly defined?  &lt;br /&gt;2. What evidence has the author produced to support this central idea? &lt;br /&gt;3. How convincing are the reasons given for the author’s point of view? &lt;br /&gt;4. Could the evidence be interpreted in other ways?  &lt;br /&gt;5. What is the author's research method (e.g. qualitative, quantitative, &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;experimental, etc.)? &lt;br /&gt;6. What is the author's theoretical framework (e.g. psychological, developmental, &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;feminist)? &lt;br /&gt;7. What is the relationship assumed by the author between theory and practice? &lt;br /&gt;8. Has the author critically evaluated the other literature in the field?  &lt;br /&gt;9. Does the author include literature opposing her/his point of view? &lt;br /&gt;10. Is the research data valid– i.e. based on a reliable method and accurate &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;information? &lt;br /&gt;11. Can you &amp;quot;deconstruct&amp;quot; the argument – identify the gaps or jumps in the logic? &lt;br /&gt;12. What are the strengths and limitations of this study? &lt;br /&gt;13. What does this book or article contribute to my own topic or thesis? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you ask these questions, make sure you also take careful notes on the &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;www.kent.ac.uk/learning &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;content of each book or journal article. You will need these notes for your later &lt;br /&gt;summary. Keep the references!  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;5. Developing the Literature Review &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A literature review is made up of a series of ‘mini book reviews’ on material &lt;br /&gt;read for the assignment. But remember: a good book review always has at &lt;br /&gt;least two distinct components: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• A brief summary of the content of the book/article together with an equally brief &lt;br /&gt;description of the importance of this piece of research for your own study – why &lt;br /&gt;include this particular book or article? Remember, most books or articles are &lt;br /&gt;usually making just ONE key point; so, what is that one point in this particular &lt;br /&gt;book/article, and how does that claim relate to your own research project or &lt;br /&gt;assignment? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• A critique of the book or article: this involves an analysis of the argument, &lt;br /&gt;including an assessment of the relative strengths and weaknesses of the &lt;br /&gt;evidence presented. Does the author produce sufficient evidence to establish the &lt;br /&gt;point they want to make? What has conveniently been left out or skated over? &lt;br /&gt;Where is the counter-argument, and has the author dealt with this adequately? &lt;br /&gt;What is the author not saying, what would contradict their argument, and so on. &lt;br /&gt;Look carefully for the holes in the presentation; remember, every author is &lt;br /&gt;spinning the evidence to make it show what they want it to show. Can you spin &lt;br /&gt;the same evidence in another direction? If so, what impact would this have on the &lt;br /&gt;overall argument? What if this particular author is completely wrong? Or, perhaps &lt;br /&gt;more likely, what if this particular author is only partially right? What difference &lt;br /&gt;would that make to your understanding of the topic? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;6. Placing the Literature Review in the Dissertation/Thesis &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is some discussion amongst academics about the position of the &lt;br /&gt;literature review: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• The ‘traditional’ place is immediately after the introduction to the dissertation or &lt;br /&gt;thesis – the second section or chapter after an initial sketch of the project  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Some scholars prefer the literature review to be placed after the presentation of &lt;br /&gt;empirical evidence so that the literature review acts as a kind of foil to the main &lt;br /&gt;findings. This is fairly common in the qualitative (broadly ethnographic) tradition &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Some scholars, especially in the qualitative tradition, prefer the literature review to &lt;br /&gt;be distributed over the assignment as a whole, so the entire dissertation or thesis &lt;br /&gt;reads like an on-going conversation between empirical research and scholarly &lt;br /&gt;theory &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, this is probably one of the (many!) things you will want to discuss with your &lt;br /&gt;supervisor. But unless you have been told otherwise, it is almost certainly &lt;br /&gt;better to play safe and put the literature review in the ‘traditional slot’ after the &lt;br /&gt;introduction. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;7. Structuring the Literature Review &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Try to build the literature review around your key topic or thesis: be relentless – &lt;br /&gt;show how each piece of literature contributes to, or challenges, your central &lt;br /&gt;theme. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The overall structure of the section or chapter should be just like any other: it &lt;br /&gt;should have a beginning, middle and end. In other words, you need to guide &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;www.kent.ac.uk/learning &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;the reader through the literature review, outlining the strategy you have &lt;br /&gt;adopted for selecting the books or articles, presenting the topic theme for the &lt;br /&gt;review, then using most of the word limit to analyse the chosen books or &lt;br /&gt;articles thoroughly before pulling everything together briefly in the conclusion. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;By far the most common approach to the central ‘presentation of the evidence’ &lt;br /&gt;section is to work systematically through the books or articles selected. A &lt;br /&gt;paragraph or two is usually enough on each item, but remember you will need &lt;br /&gt;for each book or article comments on: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• The content – a brief summary of the main ideas and evidence &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• The strengths and weaknesses of the argument – the all-important critique &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• The relevance of the book or article for your particular project: how does this &lt;br /&gt;contribute to your own thinking and/or research? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are writing a Ph.D thesis, then the literature review is typically one &lt;br /&gt;chapter (perhaps 8-10,000 words), but this can vary enormously, depending on &lt;br /&gt;your subject. Ask your supervisor! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are writing a Master’s dissertation, your literature review should probably &lt;br /&gt;be around 2-3,000 words, again depending on a wide range of factors. Ask &lt;br /&gt;your supervisor! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are writing an undergraduate dissertation, your literature review will &lt;br /&gt;probably be about 2,000 words – but the same principle applies: ask! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;One variation on the traditional linear approach is to organise your literature &lt;br /&gt;review into historical order. Others prefer to start with the main theories and &lt;br /&gt;give more space to these, leaving the less important stuff for later.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some people prefer a less linear approach. Instead of simply working through &lt;br /&gt;a list of 8-20 items on your book review list, you might want to try a thematic &lt;br /&gt;approach, grouping key ideas, facts, concepts or approaches together and &lt;br /&gt;then bouncing the ideas off each other. This is a slightly more creative (and &lt;br /&gt;interesting) way of doing the review, but a little more risky – it is easy with this &lt;br /&gt;approach to lose coherence and logical sequencing.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whichever approach you adopt, make sure everything flows smoothly – that &lt;br /&gt;one idea or book leads neatly to the next. Take your reader effortlessly through &lt;br /&gt;a sequence of thought that is clear, accurate, precise and interesting. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;8. Writing Up the Literature Review &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;As with essays generally, only attempt to write up the literature review when it &lt;br /&gt;is ‘ripe’ – that is, when you have done all the reading, note-taking and planning &lt;br /&gt;for the chapter or section, and allowed yourself adequate thinking-time’. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then start writing. Find a neat way of introducing the review, then guide the &lt;br /&gt;reader through the material clearly and directly. Use evidence – never make &lt;br /&gt;unsubstantiated claims, but back everything up with argument and data. Avoid &lt;br /&gt;too many quotes and always give references for any quotation. Sometimes &lt;br /&gt;students use long quotation as a way of padding out the essay or in an attempt &lt;br /&gt;to cover up a lack of understanding. Don’t do this: it always shows, and will be &lt;br /&gt;picked up by the marker. Always summarise material in your own words as &lt;br /&gt;much as possible. Save the quotes for ‘punch-lines’ to drive the point home.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;page-break-before:always; page-break-after:always&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;www.kent.ac.uk/learning &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Be selective in the number of points you draw out from each piece of literature; &lt;br /&gt;remember that part of the object of the exercise is to show your tutors that you can &lt;br /&gt;use your judgement to identify what is central and what is secondary  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Summarise and synthesise – use your own words to sum up what you think is &lt;br /&gt;important or controversial about the book or article &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Be cautious - never claim more than the evidence will support. Too many &lt;br /&gt;dissertations and theses are ruined by exaggerated or sweeping generalisations. &lt;br /&gt;Be tentative and careful in the way you interpret the evidence &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Keep your own voice – you are entitled to your own point of view provided it is &lt;br /&gt;based on the evidence presented. Having said that, make sure you back up your &lt;br /&gt;opinions with clear argument, and on the whole, it is usually better to avoid too &lt;br /&gt;much ‘I’ language; better to be a little more indirect and tentative (‘this tends to &lt;br /&gt;suggest’, ‘it could be argued’ and so on) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Revise, revise, revise: refine and edit the draft as much as you can. Check for &lt;br /&gt;fluency, structure, evidence and referencing. Don’t forget the basics: grammar and &lt;br /&gt;spelling! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</Content>
</Section>
</Archive>
